{
    "title": "/The Costs of Production ❖ 6",
    "icon": "<svg xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg\" class=\"h-8 w-8\" fill=\"none\" viewBox=\"0 0 24 24\" stroke=\"currentColor\" stroke-width=\"2\"><path stroke-linecap=\"round\" stroke-linejoin=\"round\" d=\"M19 11H5m14 0a2 2 0 012 2v6a2 2 0 01-2 2H5a2 2 0 01-2-2v-6a2 2 0 012-2m14 0V9a2 2 0 00-2-2M5 11V9a2 2 0 012-2m0 0V5a2 2 0 012-2h6a2 2 0 012 2v2M7 7h10\" /></svg>",
    "sectors": {
        "sector1": {
            "title": "Introduction & What are Costs?",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Supply curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Analyzing the behavior of the firm enhances our understanding of",
                    "options": [
                        "what decisions lie behind the market supply curve.",
                        "how consumers allocate their income to purchase scarce resources.",
                        "how financial institutions set interest rates.",
                        "whether resources are allocated fairly."
                    ],
                    "answer": "what decisions lie behind the market supply curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Supply curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A student might describe information about the costs of production as",
                    "options": [
                        "dry and technical.",
                        "boring.",
                        "crucial to understanding firms and market structures.",
                        "All of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above could be correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Supply curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A student might describe information about the costs of production as",
                    "options": [
                        "exciting and fresh.",
                        "unimportant for understanding market structure.",
                        "dry and technical.",
                        "vibrant and enthralling."
                    ],
                    "answer": "dry and technical.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which field of economics studies how the number of firms affects the prices in a market and the efficiency of market outcomes?",
                    "options": [
                        "macroeconomics",
                        "industrial organization",
                        "labor economics",
                        "monetary economics"
                    ],
                    "answer": "industrial organization",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists in the field of industrial organization study how",
                    "options": [
                        "central banking policies affect financial markets.",
                        "firms’ demand for labor and individuals’ supply of labor affect resource markets.",
                        "firms’ decisions about prices and quantities depend on market conditions.",
                        "externalities and public goods affect the environment."
                    ],
                    "answer": "firms’ decisions about prices and quantities depend on market conditions.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Industrial organization is the study of how",
                    "options": [
                        "labor unions organize workers in industries.",
                        "profitable firms are in organized industries.",
                        "industries organize for political advantage.",
                        "firms' decisions regarding prices and quantities depend on the market conditions they face."
                    ],
                    "answer": "firms' decisions regarding prices and quantities depend on the market conditions they face.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "To an economist, the field of industrial organization answers which of the following questions?",
                    "options": [
                        "Why are consumers subject to the law of demand?",
                        "Why do firms experience diminishing marginal products of inputs?",
                        "How does the number of firms affect prices and the efficiency of market outcomes?",
                        "Why do firms consider production costs when determining product supply?"
                    ],
                    "answer": "How does the number of firms affect prices and the efficiency of market outcomes?",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists assume that the typical person who starts her own business does so with the intention of",
                    "options": [
                        "donating the profits from her business to charity.",
                        "capturing the highest number of sales in her industry.",
                        "maximizing profits.",
                        "minimizing costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "maximizing profits.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists normally assume that the goal of a firm is to\n\n(i),sell as much of its product as possible.\n(ii),set the price of the product as high as possible.\n(iii),maximize profit.",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "(iii) only",
                        "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "(iii) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists normally assume that the goal of a firm is to earn\n\n(i),\"profits as large as possible, even if it means reducing output.\"\n(ii),\"profits as large as possible, even if it means incurring a higher total cost.\"\n(iii),\"revenues as large as possible, even if it reduces profits.\"",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(i) and (iii) only",
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "\"(i), (ii), and (iii) \""
                    ],
                    "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An entrepreneur’s motivation to start a business arises from",
                    "options": [
                        "an innate love for the type of business that he or she starts.",
                        "a desire to earn a profit.",
                        "an altruistic desire to provide the world with a good product.",
                        "All of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above could be correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists normally assume that the goal of a firm is to",
                    "options": [
                        "maximize its total revenue.",
                        "maximize its profit.",
                        "minimize its explicit costs.",
                        "minimize its total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "maximize its profit.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economists assume that the goal of the firm is to maximize total",
                    "options": [
                        "revenue.",
                        "profits.",
                        "costs.",
                        "satisfaction."
                    ],
                    "answer": "profits.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Profit maximization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a firm is making a profit-maximizing production decision, which of the following principles of economics is likely to be most important to the firm's decision?",
                    "options": [
                        "The cost of something is what you give up to get it.",
                        "A country's standard of living depends on its ability to produce goods and services.",
                        "Prices rise when the government prints too much money.",
                        "Governments can sometimes improve market outcomes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The cost of something is what you give up to get it.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The amount of money that a firm receives from the sale of its output is called",
                    "options": [
                        "total gross profit.",
                        "total net profit.",
                        "total revenue.",
                        "net revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total revenue.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue equals",
                    "options": [
                        "price x quantity.",
                        "price/quantity.",
                        "(price x quantity) - total cost.",
                        "output - input."
                    ],
                    "answer": "price x quantity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following can be added to profit to obtain total revenue?",
                    "options": [
                        "net profit",
                        "capital profit",
                        "operational profit",
                        "total cost"
                    ],
                    "answer": "total cost",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If Darren sells 300 glasses of iced tea at $0.50 each, his total revenues are",
                    "options": [
                        "$150.",
                        "$299.50.",
                        "$300.",
                        "$600."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$150.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If Tanya sells 200 glasses of fruit punch at $0.50 each, her total revenues are",
                    "options": [
                        "$100.",
                        "$199.50.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$400."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$100.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Cody builds mailboxes.  If he charges $20 for each mailbox, his total revenue will be",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$1,000 if he sells 100 mailboxes.\"",
                        "$500 if he sells 25 mailboxes.",
                        "$20 regardless of how many mailboxes he sells.",
                        "$200 if he sells 5 mailboxes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$500 if he sells 25 mailboxes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The Big Box corporation produced and sold 500 units of output.  The average cost of production per unit was $50. Each unit sold for a price of $65. The Big Box corporation’s total revenues are",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$7,500.\"",
                        "\"$25,000.\"",
                        "\"$32,500.\"",
                        "\"$67,500.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"32,500.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Trevor’s Tire Company produced and sold 500 tires. The average cost of production per tire was $50. Each tire sold for a price of $65. Trevor’s Tire Company’s total costs are",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$7,500.\"",
                        "\"$25,000.\"",
                        "\"$32,500.\"",
                        "\"$67,500.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"25,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Trevor’s Tire Company produced and sold 500 tires. The average cost of production per tire was $50. Each tire sold for a price of $65. Trevor’s Tire Company’s total profits are",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$7,500.\"",
                        "\"$25,000.\"",
                        "\"$32,500.\"",
                        "\"$67,500.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"7,500.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A certain firm manufactures and sells computer chips. Last year it sold 2 million chips at a price of $10 per chip. For last year, the firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit was $20 million.",
                        "economic profit was $20 million.",
                        "total revenue was $20 million.",
                        "explicit costs was $20 million."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total revenue was $20 million.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Total revenue",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A certain firm produces and sells potato chips. Last year it sold 3 million bags of chips at a price of $3 per bag. For last year, the firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit was $9 million.",
                        "economic profit was $9 million.",
                        "total revenue was $9 million.",
                        "explicit costs was $9 million."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total revenue was $9 million.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The amount of money that a firm pays to buy inputs is called",
                    "options": [
                        "total cost.",
                        "variable cost.",
                        "marginal cost.",
                        "fixed cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total cost is the",
                    "options": [
                        "amount a firm receives for the sale of its output.",
                        "fixed cost less variable cost.",
                        "market value of the inputs a firm uses in production.",
                        "quantity of output minus the quantity of inputs used to make a good."
                    ],
                    "answer": "market value of the inputs a firm uses in production.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Profit is defined as",
                    "options": [
                        "net revenue minus depreciation.",
                        "total revenue minus total cost.",
                        "average revenue minus average total cost.",
                        "marginal revenue minus marginal cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total revenue minus total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Profit is defined as total revenue",
                    "options": [
                        "plus total cost.",
                        "times total cost.",
                        "minus total cost.",
                        "divided by total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "minus total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Daphne sells 300 glasses of lemonade at $0.50 each.  Her total costs are $125.  Her profits are",
                    "options": [
                        "$25.",
                        "$124.50.",
                        "$125.",
                        "$150."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Joy sells 200 glasses of iced tea at $0.50 each.  Her total costs are $25.  Her profits are",
                    "options": [
                        "$25.",
                        "$75.",
                        "$100.",
                        "$175."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$75.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Billy’s Bean Bag Emporium produced 300 bean bag chairs but sold only 275 of the units it produced. The average cost of production for each unit of output produced was $100. The price for each of the 275 units sold was $95. Total profit for Billy’s Bean Bag Emporium would be",
                    "options": [
                        "\"-$3,875.\"",
                        "\"$26,125.\"",
                        "\"$28,500.\"",
                        "\"$30,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"-$3,875.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The things that must be forgone to acquire a good are called",
                    "options": [
                        "implicit costs.",
                        "opportunity costs.",
                        "explicit costs.",
                        "accounting costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "opportunity costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A firm's opportunity costs of production are equal to its",
                    "options": [
                        "explicit costs only.",
                        "implicit costs only.",
                        "explicit costs + implicit costs.",
                        "explicit costs + implicit costs + total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "explicit costs + implicit costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Wiladee used to work as an office manager, earning $25,000 per year. She gave up that job to start a tailoring business. In calculating the economic profit of her tailoring business, the $25,000 income that she gave up is counted as part of the tailoring firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "total revenue.",
                        "opportunity costs.",
                        "explicit costs.",
                        "marginal costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "opportunity costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "John has decided to start his own lawn-mowing business. To purchase the mowers and the trailer to transport the mowers, John withdrew $1,000 from his savings account, which was earning 3% interest, and borrowed an additional $2,000 from the bank at an interest rate of 7%. What is John's annual opportunity cost of the financial capital that has been invested in the business?",
                    "options": [
                        "$30",
                        "$140",
                        "$170",
                        "$300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$170",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Gloria has decided to start her own snow removal business. To purchase the necessary equipment, Gloria withdrew $2,000 from her savings account, which was earning 3% interest, and borrowed an additional $4,000 from the bank at an interest rate of 7%. What is Gloria's annual opportunity cost of the financial capital that has been invested in the business?",
                    "options": [
                        "$60",
                        "$280",
                        "$340",
                        "$660"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$340",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Zach has decided to start his own photography studio. To purchase the necessary equipment, Zach withdrew $10,000 from his savings account, which was earning 3% interest, and borrowed an additional $5,000 from the bank at an interest rate of 8%. What is Zach's annual opportunity cost of the financial capital that has been invested in the business?",
                    "options": [
                        "$300",
                        "$400",
                        "$700",
                        "\"$1,650\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "$700",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The value of a business owner's time is an example of",
                    "options": [
                        "an opportunity cost.",
                        "a fixed cost.",
                        "an explicit cost.",
                        "total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an opportunity cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An example of an opportunity cost that is also an implicit cost is",
                    "options": [
                        "a lease payment.",
                        "the cost of raw materials.",
                        "the value of the business owner’s time.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the value of the business owner’s time.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Opportunity costs equal explicit minus implicit costs.",
                        "Economists consider opportunity costs to be included in a firm’s total revenues.",
                        "Economists consider opportunity costs to be included in a firm’s costs of production.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Economists consider opportunity costs to be included in a firm’s costs of production.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Explicit costs",
                    "options": [
                        "require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                        "include all of the firm's opportunity costs.",
                        "include the value of the business owner’s time.",
                        "Both b and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An example of an explicit cost of production would be the",
                    "options": [
                        "cost of forgone labor earnings for an entrepreneur.",
                        "lost opportunity to invest in capital markets when the money is invested in one's business.",
                        "lease payments for the land on which a firm’s factory stands.",
                        "Both a and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "lease payments for the land on which a firm’s factory stands.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pete owns a shoe-shine business. His accountant most likely includes which of the following costs on his financial statements?",
                    "options": [
                        "wages Pete could earn washing windows",
                        "dividends Pete's money was earning in the stock market before Pete sold his stock and bought a shoe-shine booth",
                        "the cost of shoe polish",
                        "Both b and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the cost of shoe polish",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pete owns a shoe-shine business. His accountant most likely includes which of the following costs on his financial statements?\n\n(i),shoe polish\n(ii),rent on the shoe stand\n(iii),wages Pete could earn delivering newspapers\n(iv),interest that Pete’s money was earning before he spent his savings to set up the shoe-shine business",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) only",
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(iii) and (iv) only",
                        "\"(i), (ii), (iii), and (iv)\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Explicit costs",
                    "options": [
                        "do not require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                        "enter into the accountant's measurement of a firm's profit.",
                        "enter into the economist's measurement of a firm's profit.",
                        "Both b and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Both b and c are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs | Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A difference between explicit and implicit costs is that",
                    "options": [
                        "explicit costs must be greater than implicit costs.",
                        "\"explicit costs do not require a direct monetary outlay by the firm, whereas implicit costs do.\"",
                        "\"implicit costs do not require a direct monetary outlay by the firm, whereas explicit costs do.\"",
                        "implicit costs must be greater than explicit costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"implicit costs do not require a direct monetary outlay by the firm, whereas explicit costs do.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following would be an example of an implicit cost?\n\n(i),forgone investment opportunities\n(ii),wages of workers\n(iii),raw materials costs",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) only",
                        "(ii) only",
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "(i) and (iii) only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "(i) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pete owns a shoe-shine business. Which of the following costs would be implicit costs?\n\n(i),shoe polish\n(ii),rent on the shoe stand\n(iii),wages Pete could earn delivering newspapers\n(iv),interest that Pete’s money was earning before he spent his savings to set up the shoe-shine business",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(iv) only",
                        "(iii) and (iv) only",
                        "\"(i), (ii), (iii), and (iv)\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "(iii) and (iv) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Implicit costs",
                    "options": [
                        "do not require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                        "do not enter into the economist's measurement of a firm's profit.",
                        "are also known as variable costs.",
                        "are not part of an economist’s measurement of opportunity cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "do not require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is an example of an implicit cost?\n\n(i),the owner of a firm forgoing an opportunity to earn a large salary working for a Wall Street brokerage firm\n(ii),interest paid on the firm's debt\n(iii),rent paid by the firm to lease office space",
                    "options": [
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "(i) and (iii) only",
                        "(i) only",
                        "(iii) only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "(i) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The amount of money that a wheat farmer could have earned if he had planted barley instead of wheat is",
                    "options": [
                        "an explicit cost.",
                        "an accounting cost",
                        "an implicit cost.",
                        "forgone accounting profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an implicit cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is an example of an implicit cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "salaries paid to owners who work for the firm",
                        "interest on money borrowed to finance equipment purchases",
                        "cash payments for raw materials",
                        "foregone rent on office space owned and used by the firm"
                    ],
                    "answer": "foregone rent on office space owned and used by the firm",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Foregone investment opportunities are an example of",
                    "options": [
                        "an explicit cost.",
                        "an implicit cost.",
                        "revenues.",
                        "profits."
                    ],
                    "answer": "an implicit cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Jacqui decides to open her own business and earns $50,000 in accounting profit the first year. When deciding to open her own business, she turned down three separate job offers with annual salaries of $30,000, $40,000, and $45,000. What is Jacqui's economic profit from running her own business?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$-55,000\"",
                        "\"$-5,000\"",
                        "\"$5,000\"",
                        "\"$20,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$5,000\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Bev is opening her own court-reporting business.  She financed the business by withdrawing money from her personal savings account.  When she closed the account, the bank representative mentioned that she would have earned $300 in interest next year.  If Bev hadn’t opened her own business, she would have earned a salary of $25,000.  In her first year, Bev’s revenues were $30,000.  Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"Bev’s total explicit costs are $25,300.\"",
                        "Bev’s total implicit costs are $300.",
                        "Bev’s accounting profits exceed her economic profits by $300.",
                        "\"Bev’s economic profit is $4,700.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"Bev’s economic profit is $4,700.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Walter used to work as a high school teacher for $40,000 per year but quit in order to start his own painting business. To invest in his painting business, he withdrew $20,000 from his savings, which paid 3 percent interest, and borrowed $30,000 from his uncle, whom he pays 3 percent interest per year. Last year Walter paid $25,000 for supplies and had revenue of $60,000. Walter asked Tyler the accountant and Greg the economist to calculate his painting business’s costs.",
                    "options": [
                        "\"Tyler says his costs are $25,900, and Greg says his costs are $66,500.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his costs are $25,000, and Greg says his costs are $65,000.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his costs are $66,500, and Greg says his costs are $66,500.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his costs are $75,000, and Greg says his costs are $41,500.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"Tyler says his costs are $25,900, and Greg says his costs are $66,500.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Walter used to work as a high school teacher for $40,000 per year but quit in order to start his own painting business. To invest in his painting business, he withdrew $20,000 from his savings, which paid 3 percent interest, and borrowed $30,000 from his uncle, whom he pays 3 percent interest per year. Last year Walter paid $25,000 for supplies and had revenue of $60,000. Walter asked Tyler the accountant and Greg the economist to calculate his painting business’s profit.",
                    "options": [
                        "\"Tyler says his profit is $25,900, and Greg says his profit is $66,500.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his profit is $35,000, and Greg says he lost $5,900.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his profit is $34,100, and Greg says he lost $6,500.\"",
                        "\"Tyler says his profit is $34,100, and Greg says his profit is $34,100.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"Tyler says his profit is $34,100, and Greg says he lost $6,500.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"Assuming that explicit costs are positive, economic profit is greater than accounting profit.\"",
                        "\"Assuming that implicit costs are positive, accounting profit is greater than economic profit.\"",
                        "\"Assuming that explicit costs are positive, accounting profit is equal to economic profit.\"",
                        "\"Assuming that implicit costs are positive, economic profit is positive.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"Assuming that implicit costs are positive, accounting profit is greater than economic profit.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Katherine gives piano lessons for $15 per hour.  She also grows flowers, which she arranges and sells at the local farmer’s market.  One day she spends 5 hours planting $50 worth of seeds in her garden.  Once the seeds have grown into flowers, she can sell them for $150 at the farmer’s market.  Katherine’s accounting profits are",
                    "options": [
                        "\" $100, and her economic profits are $25.\"",
                        "\"$100, and her economic profits are $75.\"",
                        "\"$25, and her economic profits are $100.\"",
                        "\"$75, and her economic profits are $125.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\" $100, and her economic profits are $25.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Katherine gives piano lessons for $20 per hour.  She also grows flowers, which she arranges and sells at the local farmer’s market.  One day she spends 5 hours planting $50 worth of seeds in her garden.  Once the seeds have grown into flowers, she can sell them for $150 at the farmer’s market.  Katherine’s accounting profits are",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$100, and her economic profits are $100.\"",
                        "\"$100, and her economic profits are $0.\"",
                        "\"$0, and her economic profits are $100.\"",
                        "\"$0, and her economic profits are $-100.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$100, and her economic profits are $0.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit | Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The difference between accounting profit and economic profit is\t",
                    "options": [
                        "explicit costs.",
                        "implicit costs.",
                        "total revenue.",
                        "marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "implicit costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economic profit is equal to total revenue minus the",
                    "options": [
                        "explicit cost of producing goods and services.",
                        "opportunity cost of producing goods and services.",
                        "accounting cost of producing goods and services.",
                        "implicit cost of producing goods and services."
                    ],
                    "answer": "opportunity cost of producing goods and services.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economic profit",
                    "options": [
                        "will never exceed accounting profit.",
                        "is most often equal to accounting profit.",
                        "is always at least as large as accounting profit.",
                        "is a less complete measure of profitability than accounting profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "will never exceed accounting profit.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When calculating a firm's profit, an economist will subtract only",
                    "options": [
                        "explicit costs from total revenue because these are the only costs that can be measured explicitly.",
                        "implicit costs from total revenue because these include both the costs that can be directly measured as well as the costs that can be indirectly measured.",
                        "the opportunity costs from total revenue because these include both the implicit and explicit costs of the firm.",
                        "the marginal cost because the cost of the next unit is the only relevant cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the opportunity costs from total revenue because these include both the implicit and explicit costs of the firm.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue minus both explicit and implicit costs is called",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit.",
                        "economic profit.",
                        "average total cost.",
                        "total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "economic profit.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue minus only explicit costs is called",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit.",
                        "economic profit.",
                        "average total cost.",
                        "implicit profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "accounting profit.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total revenue minus only implicit costs is called",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit.",
                        "economic profit.",
                        "opportunity cost.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Tom quit his $65,000 a year corporate lawyer job to open up his own law practice. In Tom's first year in business his total revenue equaled $150,000. Tom's explicit cost during the year totaled $85,000. What is Tom’s economic profit for his first year in business?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0",
                        "\"$20,000\"",
                        "\"$65,000\"",
                        "\"$85,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "$0",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The difference between accounting profit and economic profit relates to",
                    "options": [
                        "the manner in which revenues are defined.",
                        "how marginal revenue is calculated.",
                        "the manner in which costs are defined.",
                        "the price of the good in the market."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the manner in which costs are defined.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Jane was a partner at a law firm earning $223,000 per year. She left the firm to open her own law practice. In the first year of business she generated revenues of $347,000 and incurred explicit costs of $163,000. Jane’s economic profit from her first year in her own practice is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"-$39,000.\"",
                        "\"$124,000.\"",
                        "\"$163,000.\"",
                        "\"$184,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"-39,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Accounting profit is equal to",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal revenue minus marginal cost.",
                        "total revenue minus the explicit cost of producing goods and services.",
                        "total revenue minus the opportunity cost of producing goods and services.",
                        "average revenue minus the average cost of producing the last unit of a good or service."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total revenue minus the explicit cost of producing goods and services.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit = total revenue - explicit costs",
                        "economic profit = total revenue - implicit costs",
                        "economic profit = total revenue - explicit costs",
                        "Both a and b are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "accounting profit = total revenue - explicit costs",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit = economic profit + implicit costs",
                        "accounting profit = total revenue - implicit costs",
                        "economic profit = accounting profit + explicit costs",
                        "economic profit = total revenue - implicit costs"
                    ],
                    "answer": "accounting profit = economic profit + implicit costs",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit  | Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular business there are no implicit costs. Then",
                    "options": [
                        "accounting profit will be greater than economic profit.",
                        "accounting profit will be the same as economic profit.",
                        "accounting profit will be less than economic profit.",
                        "the relationship between accounting profit and economic profit cannot be determined without more information."
                    ],
                    "answer": "accounting profit will be the same as economic profit.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs | Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-1\nCalvin wants to start his own business making candles.  He can purchase a candle factory that costs $400,000. Calvin currently has $500,000 in the bank earning 3 percent interest per year. Refer to Scenario 13-1 . If Calvin purchases the factory with his own money, what is the annual implicit opportunity cost of purchasing the factory?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0",
                        "\"$3,000\"",
                        "\"$12,000\"",
                        "\"$15,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$12,000\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-1\nCalvin wants to start his own business making candles.  He can purchase a candle factory that costs $400,000. Calvin currently has $500,000 in the bank earning 3 percent interest per year. Refer to Scenario 13-1 . Suppose Calvin purchases the factory using $200,000 of his own money and $200,000 borrowed from a bank at an interest rate of 6 percent. What is Calvin’s annual opportunity cost of purchasing the factory?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$3,000\"",
                        "\"$6,000\"",
                        "\"$15,000\"",
                        "\"$18,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$18,000\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs | Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-2\nChelsea wants to start her own Christmas ornament business.  She can purchase a suitable factory that costs $100,000. Chelsea currently has $150,000 in the bank earning 3 percent interest per year. Refer to Scenario 13-2 . Suppose Chelsea purchases the factory using her own money. What is Chelsea’s annual implicit opportunity cost of purchasing the factory?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$2,000\"",
                        "\"$3,000\"",
                        "\"$4,500\"",
                        "\"$5,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$3,000\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-2\nChelsea wants to start her own Christmas ornament business.  She can purchase a suitable factory that costs $100,000. Chelsea currently has $150,000 in the bank earning 3 percent interest per year. Refer to Scenario 13-2 . Suppose Chelsea purchases the factory using $50,000 of her own money and $50,000 borrowed from a bank at an interest rate of 6 percent. What is Chelsea’s annual opportunity cost of purchasing the factory?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$2,000\"",
                        "\"$3,000\"",
                        "\"$4,500\"",
                        "\"$5,000\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$4,500\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-3\nGary is a senior majoring in computer network development at Smart State University. While he has been attending college, Gary started a computer consulting business to help senior citizens set up their network connections and teach them how to use e-mail. Gary charges $25 per hour for his consulting services. Gary also works 5 hours a week for the Economics Department to maintain that department's Web page. The Economics Department pays Gary $20 per hour. Refer to Scenario 13-3.   If Gary can work additional hours at either job, what is the opportunity cost if Gary spends one hour reading a novel?",
                    "options": [
                        "$20",
                        "$25",
                        "$100",
                        "$125"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-3\nGary is a senior majoring in computer network development at Smart State University. While he has been attending college, Gary started a computer consulting business to help senior citizens set up their network connections and teach them how to use e-mail. Gary charges $25 per hour for his consulting services. Gary also works 5 hours a week for the Economics Department to maintain that department's Web page. The Economics Department pays Gary $20 per hour. Refer to Scenario 13-3.   Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Gary should increase the number of hours he works for the Economics Department to make it comparable to his consulting business income.",
                        "Gary is not maximizing his well-being if he continues to work for the Economics Department.",
                        "\"If Gary chooses one hour at the beach with his friends rather than spend one more hour with a consulting client, the forgone income of $25 is considered a cost of the choice to go to the beach.\"",
                        "Both b) and c) are correct"
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"If Gary chooses one hour at the beach with his friends rather than spend one more hour with a consulting client, the forgone income of $25 is considered a cost of the choice to go to the beach.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-4\nSuppose that Abdul opens a coffee shop.  He receives a loan from a bank for $100,000.  He withdraws $50,000 from his personal savings account.  The interest rate on the loan is 8%, and the interest rate on his savings account is 2%. Refer to Scenario 13-4.   Abdul’s explicit cost of capital is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$8,000.\"",
                        "\"$4,000.\"",
                        "\"$2,000.\"",
                        "\"$1,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$8,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-4\nSuppose that Abdul opens a coffee shop.  He receives a loan from a bank for $100,000.  He withdraws $50,000 from his personal savings account.  The interest rate on the loan is 8%, and the interest rate on his savings account is 2%. Refer to Scenario 13-4.   Abdul’s implicit cost of capital is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$8,000.\"",
                        "\"$4,000.\"",
                        "\"$2,000.\"",
                        "\"$1,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$1,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-5\nSuppose that Emily opens a restaurant.  She receives a loan from a bank for $200,000.  She withdraws $100,000 from her personal savings account.  The interest rate on the loan is 6%, and the interest rate on her savings account is 2%. Refer to Scenario 13-5.   Emily’s explicit cost of capital is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$2,000.\"",
                        "\"$4,000.\"",
                        "\"$12,000.\"",
                        "\"$14,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$12,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-5\nSuppose that Emily opens a restaurant.  She receives a loan from a bank for $200,000.  She withdraws $100,000 from her personal savings account.  The interest rate on the loan is 6%, and the interest rate on her savings account is 2%. Refer to Scenario 13-5.   Emily’s implicit cost of capital is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$2,000.\"",
                        "\"$4,000.\"",
                        "\"$12,000.\"",
                        "\"$14,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$2,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-5\nSuppose that Emily opens a restaurant.  She receives a loan from a bank for $200,000.  She withdraws $100,000 from her personal savings account.  The interest rate on the loan is 6%, and the interest rate on her savings account is 2%. Refer to Scenario 13-5.   Emily’s total opportunity cost of capital is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$2,000.\"",
                        "\"$4,000.\"",
                        "\"$12,000.\"",
                        "\"$14,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$14,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-6\nTony is a wheat farmer, but he also spends part of his day teaching guitar lessons. Due to the popularity of his local country western band, Farmer Tony has more students requesting lessons than he has time for if he is to also maintain his farming business. Farmer Tony charges $25 an hour for his guitar lessons. One spring day, he spends 10 hours in his fields planting $130 worth of seeds on his farm. He expects that the seeds he planted will yield $300 worth of wheat. Refer to Scenario 13-6 . What is the total opportunity cost of the day that Farmer Tony spent in the field planting wheat?",
                    "options": [
                        "$130",
                        "$250",
                        "$300",
                        "$380"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$380",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-6\nTony is a wheat farmer, but he also spends part of his day teaching guitar lessons. Due to the popularity of his local country western band, Farmer Tony has more students requesting lessons than he has time for if he is to also maintain his farming business. Farmer Tony charges $25 an hour for his guitar lessons. One spring day, he spends 10 hours in his fields planting $130 worth of seeds on his farm. He expects that the seeds he planted will yield $300 worth of wheat. Refer to Scenario 13-6 . An economist would calculate Tony's total cost to equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$130.",
                        "$250.",
                        "$300.",
                        "$380."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$380.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-6\nTony is a wheat farmer, but he also spends part of his day teaching guitar lessons. Due to the popularity of his local country western band, Farmer Tony has more students requesting lessons than he has time for if he is to also maintain his farming business. Farmer Tony charges $25 an hour for his guitar lessons. One spring day, he spends 10 hours in his fields planting $130 worth of seeds on his farm. He expects that the seeds he planted will yield $300 worth of wheat. Refer to Scenario 13-6 . Tony's accountant would calculate the total cost of his farming to equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$25.",
                        "$130.",
                        "$300.",
                        "$380."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$130.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-6\nTony is a wheat farmer, but he also spends part of his day teaching guitar lessons. Due to the popularity of his local country western band, Farmer Tony has more students requesting lessons than he has time for if he is to also maintain his farming business. Farmer Tony charges $25 an hour for his guitar lessons. One spring day, he spends 10 hours in his fields planting $130 worth of seeds on his farm. He expects that the seeds he planted will yield $300 worth of wheat. Refer to Scenario 13-6 . Tony's accounting profit equals",
                    "options": [
                        "$-80.",
                        "$130.",
                        "$170.",
                        "$260."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$170.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-6\nTony is a wheat farmer, but he also spends part of his day teaching guitar lessons. Due to the popularity of his local country western band, Farmer Tony has more students requesting lessons than he has time for if he is to also maintain his farming business. Farmer Tony charges $25 an hour for his guitar lessons. One spring day, he spends 10 hours in his fields planting $130 worth of seeds on his farm. He expects that the seeds he planted will yield $300 worth of wheat. Refer to Scenario 13-6 . Tony's economic profit equals",
                    "options": [
                        "$-130.",
                        "$-80.",
                        "$130.",
                        "$170."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$-80.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-7\nWanda owns a lemonade stand.  She produces lemonade using five inputs:  water, sugar, lemons, paper cups, and labor.  Her costs per glass are as follows:  $0.01 for water, $0.02 for sugar, $0.03 for lemons, $0.02 for cups, and $0.10 for the opportunity cost of her labor.  She can sell 300 glasses for $0.50 each. Refer to Scenario 13-7.   What are Wanda’s explicit costs per glass?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0.18",
                        "$0.10",
                        "$0.08",
                        "$0.02"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$0.08",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-7\nWanda owns a lemonade stand.  She produces lemonade using five inputs:  water, sugar, lemons, paper cups, and labor.  Her costs per glass are as follows:  $0.01 for water, $0.02 for sugar, $0.03 for lemons, $0.02 for cups, and $0.10 for the opportunity cost of her labor.  She can sell 300 glasses for $0.50 each. Refer to Scenario 13-7.   What are Wanda’s implicit costs per glass?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0.18",
                        "$0.10",
                        "$0.08",
                        "$0.02"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$0.10",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-7\nWanda owns a lemonade stand.  She produces lemonade using five inputs:  water, sugar, lemons, paper cups, and labor.  Her costs per glass are as follows:  $0.01 for water, $0.02 for sugar, $0.03 for lemons, $0.02 for cups, and $0.10 for the opportunity cost of her labor.  She can sell 300 glasses for $0.50 each. Refer to Scenario 13-7.   What are Wanda’s total economic costs per glass?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0.18",
                        "$0.10",
                        "$0.08",
                        "$0.02"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$0.18",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-7\nWanda owns a lemonade stand.  She produces lemonade using five inputs:  water, sugar, lemons, paper cups, and labor.  Her costs per glass are as follows:  $0.01 for water, $0.02 for sugar, $0.03 for lemons, $0.02 for cups, and $0.10 for the opportunity cost of her labor.  She can sell 300 glasses for $0.50 each. Refer to Scenario 13-7.   What are Wanda’s total accounting profits?",
                    "options": [
                        "$150",
                        "$126",
                        "$96",
                        "$24"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$126",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-7\nWanda owns a lemonade stand.  She produces lemonade using five inputs:  water, sugar, lemons, paper cups, and labor.  Her costs per glass are as follows:  $0.01 for water, $0.02 for sugar, $0.03 for lemons, $0.02 for cups, and $0.10 for the opportunity cost of her labor.  She can sell 300 glasses for $0.50 each. Refer to Scenario 13-7.   What are Wanda’s total economic profits?",
                    "options": [
                        "$150",
                        "$126",
                        "$96",
                        "$54"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$96",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-8\nEllie has been working for an engineering firm and earning an annual salary of $80,000. She decides to open her own engineering business. Her annual expenses will include $15,000 for office rent, $3,000 for equipment rental, $1,000 for supplies, $1,200 for utilities, and a $35,000 salary for a secretary/bookkeeper. Ellie will cover her start-up expenses by cashing in a $20,000 certificate of deposit on which she was earning annual interest of $500. Refer to Scenario 13-8.   Ellie's annual implicit costs will equal",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$55,200.\"",
                        "\"$75,200.\"",
                        "\"$80,500.\"",
                        "\"$165,700.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$80,500.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-8\nEllie has been working for an engineering firm and earning an annual salary of $80,000. She decides to open her own engineering business. Her annual expenses will include $15,000 for office rent, $3,000 for equipment rental, $1,000 for supplies, $1,200 for utilities, and a $35,000 salary for a secretary/bookkeeper. Ellie will cover her start-up expenses by cashing in a $20,000 certificate of deposit on which she was earning annual interest of $500. Refer to Scenario 13-8.   Ellie's annual accounting costs will equal",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$55,200.\"",
                        "\"$75,200.\"",
                        "\"$80,500.\"",
                        "\"$165,700.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$55,200.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs  | Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-8\nEllie has been working for an engineering firm and earning an annual salary of $80,000. She decides to open her own engineering business. Her annual expenses will include $15,000 for office rent, $3,000 for equipment rental, $1,000 for supplies, $1,200 for utilities, and a $35,000 salary for a secretary/bookkeeper. Ellie will cover her start-up expenses by cashing in a $20,000 certificate of deposit on which she was earning annual interest of $500. Refer to Scenario 13-8.   Ellie's annual economic costs will equal",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$55,200.\"",
                        "\"$75,200.\"",
                        "\"$80,500.\"",
                        "\"$135,700.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$135,700.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-8\nEllie has been working for an engineering firm and earning an annual salary of $80,000. She decides to open her own engineering business. Her annual expenses will include $15,000 for office rent, $3,000 for equipment rental, $1,000 for supplies, $1,200 for utilities, and a $35,000 salary for a secretary/bookkeeper. Ellie will cover her start-up expenses by cashing in a $20,000 certificate of deposit on which she was earning annual interest of $500. Refer to Scenario 13-8.   According to Ellie’s accountant, which of the following revenue totals will yield her business $50,000 in profits?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$55,200\"",
                        "\"$105,200\"",
                        "\"$132,500\"",
                        "\"$185,700\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$105,200\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Scenario 13-8.   According to an economist, which of the following revenue totals will yield Ellie’s business $50,000 in economic profits?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$55,200\"",
                        "\"$100,200\"",
                        "\"$132,500\"",
                        "\"$185,700\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$185,700\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-9\nJessica makes photo frames.  She spends $5 on the materials for each photo frame.  She can create one photo frame in an hour.  She earns $10 per hour at a part-time job at the local coffee shop.  She can sell a photo frame for $30 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-9.   An accountant would calculate the total cost for one photo frame to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$5.",
                        "$10.",
                        "$15.",
                        "$25."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs | Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-9\nJessica makes photo frames.  She spends $5 on the materials for each photo frame.  She can create one photo frame in an hour.  She earns $10 per hour at a part-time job at the local coffee shop.  She can sell a photo frame for $30 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-9.   An economist would calculate the total cost for one photo frame to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$5.",
                        "$10.",
                        "$15.",
                        "$25."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-9\nJessica makes photo frames.  She spends $5 on the materials for each photo frame.  She can create one photo frame in an hour.  She earns $10 per hour at a part-time job at the local coffee shop.  She can sell a photo frame for $30 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-9.   An accountant would calculate the total profit for one photo frame to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$10.",
                        "$15.",
                        "$20.",
                        "$25."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-9\nJessica makes photo frames.  She spends $5 on the materials for each photo frame.  She can create one photo frame in an hour.  She earns $10 per hour at a part-time job at the local coffee shop.  She can sell a photo frame for $30 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-9.   An economist would calculate the total profit for one photo frame to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$10.",
                        "$15.",
                        "$20.",
                        "$25."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   The explicit cost for one birdhouse is",
                    "options": [
                        "$4.",
                        "$5.",
                        "$8.",
                        "$9."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   The implicit cost for one birdhouse is",
                    "options": [
                        "$4.",
                        "$5.",
                        "$8.",
                        "$9."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$4.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 101,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   An accountant would calculate the total cost for one birdhouse to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$5.",
                        "$8.",
                        "$9.",
                        "$13."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 102,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs | Implicit costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   An economist would calculate the total cost for one birdhouse to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$5.",
                        "$8.",
                        "$9.",
                        "$13."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$9.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   An accountant would calculate the total profit for one birdhouse to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$7.",
                        "$11.",
                        "$12.",
                        "$15."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 104,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-10\nWalter builds birdhouses.  He spends $5 on the materials for each birdhouse.  He can build one in 30 minutes.  He is semi-retired but earns $8 per hour at the local hardware store.  He can sell a birdhouse for $20 each.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-10.   An economist would calculate the total profit for one birdhouse to be",
                    "options": [
                        "$7.",
                        "$11.",
                        "$12.",
                        "$15."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$11.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 105,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-11\nZach withdrew $400,000 out of his personal savings account and used it to start his new cookie business. The bank account pays 3 percent interest per year. During the first year of his business, Zach sold 6,000 boxes of cookies for $2.50 per box. Also during the first year, the cookie business made monetary outlays of $9,000.  You may assume that there is no opportunity cost to Zach’s time.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-11.  Zach's accounting profit for the year was",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$-494,000.\"",
                        "\"$-6,000.\"",
                        "\"$6,000.\"",
                        "\"$12,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$6,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 106,
                    "topic": "Economic profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-11\nZach withdrew $400,000 out of his personal savings account and used it to start his new cookie business. The bank account pays 3 percent interest per year. During the first year of his business, Zach sold 6,000 boxes of cookies for $2.50 per box. Also during the first year, the cookie business made monetary outlays of $9,000.  You may assume that there is no opportunity cost to Zach’s time.\n\t Refer to Scenario 13-11 . Zach's economic profit for the year was",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$-506,000.\"",
                        "\"$-6,000.\"",
                        "\"$3,000.\"",
                        "\"$6,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$-6,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector2": {
            "title": "Production and Costs",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 107,
                    "topic": "Production function  | Short run",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of these assumptions is often realistic for a firm in the short run?",
                    "options": [
                        "The firm can vary both the size of its factory and the number of workers it employs.",
                        "The firm can vary the size of its factory but not the number of workers it employs.",
                        "The firm can vary the number of workers it employs but not the size of its factory.",
                        "The firm can vary neither the size of its factory nor the number of workers it employs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The firm can vary the number of workers it employs but not the size of its factory.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 108,
                    "topic": "Production function  | Short run",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume a certain firm regards the number of workers it employs as variable but regards the size of its factory as fixed. This assumption is often realistic",
                    "options": [
                        "in the short run but not in the long run.",
                        "in the long run but not in the short run.",
                        "both in the short run and in the long run.",
                        "neither in the short run nor in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "in the short run but not in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "Production function  | Short run",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that a “doggie day care” firm uses only two inputs:  hourly workers (labor) and a building (capital).  In the short run, the firm most likely considers",
                    "options": [
                        "both labor and capital to be fixed.",
                        "both labor and capital to be variable.",
                        "labor to be variable and capital to be fixed.",
                        "capital to be variable and labor to be fixed."
                    ],
                    "answer": "labor to be variable and capital to be fixed.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 110,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A production function describes",
                    "options": [
                        "how a firm maximizes profits.",
                        "how a firm turns inputs into output.",
                        "the minimal cost of producing a given level of output.",
                        "the relationship between cost and output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "how a firm turns inputs into output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 111,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A production function is a relationship between inputs and",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity of output.",
                        "revenue.",
                        "costs.",
                        "profit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 112,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a firm uses labor to produce output, the firm’s production function depicts the relationship between",
                    "options": [
                        "the number of workers and the quantity of output.",
                        "marginal product and marginal cost.",
                        "the maximum quantity that the firm can produce as it adds more capital to a fixed quantity of labor.",
                        "fixed inputs and variable inputs in the short run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the number of workers and the quantity of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 113,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a firm, the production function represents the relationship between",
                    "options": [
                        "implicit costs and explicit costs.",
                        "quantity of inputs and total cost.",
                        "quantity of inputs and quantity of output.",
                        "quantity of output and total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity of inputs and quantity of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 114,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a firm, the relationship between the quantity of inputs and quantity of output is called the",
                    "options": [
                        "profit function.",
                        "production function.",
                        "total-cost function.",
                        "quantity function."
                    ],
                    "answer": "production function.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 115,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-1 . Suppose the production function shifts from TP1 to TP2.  Such a shift in the total product curve is most likely due to an increase in the firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "costs of production.",
                        "productivity.",
                        "product price.",
                        "market share."
                    ],
                    "answer": "productivity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 116,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-1 . Suppose the production function shifts from TP2 to TP1.  Such a shift in the total product curve is most likely due to a decrease in the firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "costs of production.",
                        "product price.",
                        "market share.",
                        "productivity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "productivity.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 117,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-1 . Which of the following could explain why the total product curve would shift from TP1 to TP2?",
                    "options": [
                        "There is less capital equipment available to the firm.",
                        "Labor skills have become rusty and outdated in the firm.",
                        "The firm has developed improved production technology.",
                        "The firm is now receiving a higher price for its product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The firm has developed improved production technology.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 118,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-1 . Which of the following could explain why the total product curve would shift from TP2 to TP1?",
                    "options": [
                        "There is additional capital equipment available to the firm.",
                        "Labor skills have become rusty and outdated in the firm.",
                        "The firm has developed improved production technology.",
                        "The firm is now receiving a higher price for its product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Labor skills have become rusty and outdated in the firm.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 119,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Grace is a self-employed artist.  She can make 20 pieces of pottery per week.  She is considering hiring her sister Kate to work for her.  Both she and Kate can make 35 pieces of pottery per week.  What is Kate’s marginal product?",
                    "options": [
                        "55 pieces of pottery",
                        "35 pieces of pottery",
                        "22.5 pieces of pottery",
                        "15 pieces of pottery"
                    ],
                    "answer": "15 pieces of pottery",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 120,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Grace is a self-employed artist.  She can make 20 pieces of pottery per week.  She is considering hiring her sister Kate to work for her.  Kate can make 18 pieces of pottery per week.  What would be the total output of Grace’s firm if she hired her sister?",
                    "options": [
                        "18 pieces of pottery",
                        "19 pieces of pottery",
                        "20 pieces of pottery",
                        "38 pieces of pottery"
                    ],
                    "answer": "38 pieces of pottery",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 121,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The marginal product of labor is equal to the",
                    "options": [
                        "incremental cost associated with a one unit increase in labor.",
                        "incremental profit associated with a one unit increase in labor.",
                        "increase in labor necessary to generate a one unit increase in output.",
                        "increase in output obtained from a one unit increase in labor."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in output obtained from a one unit increase in labor.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 122,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The marginal product of labor can be defined as the change in",
                    "options": [
                        "profit divided by the change in labor.",
                        "output divided by the change in labor.",
                        "labor divided by the change in output.",
                        "labor divided by the change in total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "output divided by the change in labor.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 123,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The marginal product of an input in the production process is the increase in",
                    "options": [
                        "total revenue obtained from an additional unit of that input.",
                        "profit obtained from an additional unit of that input.",
                        "total revenue obtained from an additional unit of that input.",
                        "quantity of output obtained from an additional unit of that input."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity of output obtained from an additional unit of that input.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 124,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a firm's only variable input is labor, then the slope of the production function measures the",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity of labor.",
                        "quantity of output.",
                        "total cost.",
                        "marginal product of labor."
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal product of labor.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 125,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Let L represent the number of workers hired by a firm, and let Q represent that firm's quantity of output. Assume two points on the firm's production function are ( L  = 12,  Q  = 122) and ( L  = 13,  Q  = 132). Then the marginal product of the 13th worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "8 units of output.",
                        "10 units of output.",
                        "122 units of output.",
                        "132 units of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "10 units of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 126,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Let L represent the number of workers hired by a firm, and let Q represent that firm's quantity of output. Assume two points on the firm's production function are ( L  = 5,  Q  = 125) and ( L  = 6,  Q  = 162). Then the marginal product of the 6th worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "25 units of output.",
                        "27 units of output.",
                        "37 units of output.",
                        "162 units of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "37 units of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 127,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Let L represent the number of workers hired by a firm, and let Q represent that firm’s quantity of output. Assume two points on the firm’s production function are ( L =6, Q =147) and ( L =7, Q =174). The marginal product of the seventh worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "25 units of output.",
                        "27 units of output.",
                        "37 units of output.",
                        "174 units of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "27 units of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 128,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a certain firm is able to produce 165 units of output per day when 15 workers are hired. The firm is able to produce 176 units of output per day when 16 workers are hired, holding other inputs fixed. The marginal product of the 16th worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "10 units of output.",
                        "11 units of output.",
                        "16 units of output.",
                        "176 units of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "11 units of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 129,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a firm currently produces 225 units of output per day with 15 workers. The firm is able to produce 235 units of output with a 16th worker. What is the marginal product of the 16th worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "10 units of output",
                        "15 units of output",
                        "16 units of output",
                        "25 units of output"
                    ],
                    "answer": "10 units of output",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 130,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The marginal product of any input is the",
                    "options": [
                        "increase in total cost associated with a one-unit increase in production.",
                        "change in total output associated with a $1.00 increase in total cost.",
                        "increase in total cost resulting from the hiring of an additional worker.",
                        "increase in total output obtained from one additional unit of that input."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increase in total output obtained from one additional unit of that input.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 131,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Eldin is a house painter. He can paint three houses per week. He is considering hiring his friend Murphy. Together, Eldin and Murphy can paint five houses per week. What is Murphy’s marginal product?",
                    "options": [
                        "2 houses",
                        "3 houses",
                        "5 houses",
                        "8 houses"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2 houses",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 132,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Eldin is a house painter. He can paint three houses per week. He is considering hiring his friend Murphy. Murphy can paint five houses per week. What is the maximum total output possible if Eldin hires Murphy?",
                    "options": [
                        "2 houses",
                        "3 houses",
                        "5 houses",
                        "8 houses"
                    ],
                    "answer": "8 houses",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 133,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-1 . What is total output when 1 worker is hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "30",
                        "40",
                        "120",
                        "160"
                    ],
                    "answer": "30",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 134,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-1 . What is total output when 2 workers are hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "10",
                        "40",
                        "70",
                        "120"
                    ],
                    "answer": "70",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 135,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-1 . What is total output when 3 workers are hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "10",
                        "40",
                        "70",
                        "120"
                    ],
                    "answer": "120",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 136,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-1 . What is total output when 4 workers are hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "-10",
                        "70",
                        "120",
                        "160"
                    ],
                    "answer": "160",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 137,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-1 . What is total output when 5 workers are hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "-10",
                        "120",
                        "160",
                        "190"
                    ],
                    "answer": "160",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 138,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-2 . What is the marginal product of the first worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "250 units",
                        "200 units",
                        "150 units",
                        "50 units"
                    ],
                    "answer": "200 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 139,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-2 . What is the marginal product of the second worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "250 units",
                        "200 units",
                        "150 units",
                        "50 units"
                    ],
                    "answer": "250 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 140,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-2 . What is the marginal product of the third worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "250 units",
                        "200 units",
                        "150 units",
                        "50 units"
                    ],
                    "answer": "150 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 141,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-2 . What is the marginal product of the fourth worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "250 units",
                        "200 units",
                        "150 units",
                        "50 units"
                    ],
                    "answer": "50 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 142,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-2 . At which number of workers does diminishing marginal product begin?",
                    "options": [
                        "1",
                        "2",
                        "3",
                        "4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "3",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 143,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-3.   The marginal product of the second worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "90 units.",
                        "85 units.",
                        "80 units.",
                        "20 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "80 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-3. The marginal product of the third worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "230 units.",
                        "100 units.",
                        "77 units.",
                        "60 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "60 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-3 . The marginal product of the fourth worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "10 units.",
                        "60 units.",
                        "230 units.",
                        "240 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "10 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-3 . At which number of workers does diminishing marginal product begin?",
                    "options": [
                        "1",
                        "2",
                        "3",
                        "4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "2",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-3. If the firm can sell its output for $1 per unit, what is the profit-maximizing level of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "240 units",
                        "230 units",
                        "190 units",
                        "170 units"
                    ],
                    "answer": "230 units",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When adding another unit of labor leads to an increase in output that is smaller than the increases in output that resulted from adding previous units of labor, the firm is experiencing",
                    "options": [
                        "diminishing labor.",
                        "diminishing output.",
                        "diminishing marginal product.",
                        "negative marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "On a 100-acre farm, a farmer is able to produce 3,000 bushels of wheat when he hires 2 workers. He is able to produce 4,400 bushels of wheat when he hires 3 workers. Which of the following possibilities is consistent with the property of diminishing marginal product?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,600 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,800 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 6,000 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,600 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "On a 100-acre farm, a farmer is able to produce 3,000 bushels of wheat when he hires 2 workers. He is able to produce 4,400 bushels of wheat when he hires 3 workers. Which of the following possibilities is consistent with the property of diminishing marginal product?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,600 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,400 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "\"The farmer is able to produce 5,200 bushels of wheat when he hires 4 workers.\"",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Any of the above could be correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When the marginal product of an input declines as the quantity of that input increases, the production function exhibits",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing marginal product.",
                        "diminishing marginal product.",
                        "diminishing total product.",
                        "Both b and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "As Bubba's Bubble Gum Company adds workers while using the same amount of machinery, some workers may be underutilized because they have little work to do while waiting in line to use the machinery. When this occurs, Bubba’s Bubble Gum Company encounters",
                    "options": [
                        "economies of scale.",
                        "diseconomies of scale.",
                        "increasing marginal product.",
                        "diminishing marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a production function shows declining marginal product of an input as the quantity of the input increases, then the production function exhibits",
                    "options": [
                        "diminishing profitability.",
                        "increasing returns to scale.",
                        "increasing marginal product.",
                        "decreasing marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreasing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-2. The graph illustrates a typical",
                    "options": [
                        "total-cost curve.",
                        "production function.",
                        "production possibilities frontier.",
                        "marginal product of labor curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "production function.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-2 . As the number of workers increases,",
                    "options": [
                        "total output increases but at a decreasing rate.",
                        "marginal product increases but at a decreasing rate.",
                        "marginal product increases at an increasing rate.",
                        "total output decreases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total output increases but at a decreasing rate.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-2 . As the number of workers increases,",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal product decreases.",
                        "total output decreases.",
                        "marginal product increases but at a decreasing rate.",
                        "Both a and b are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal product decreases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-2 . If the figure represented production at a cookie factory, the factory would be experiencing",
                    "options": [
                        "diminishing marginal product of workers.",
                        "diminishing marginal cost of cookie production.",
                        "decreasing cost of cookie production.",
                        "decreasing output of cookies."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product of workers.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Production function | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-2. The graph illustrates a typical production function. Based on its shape, what does the corresponding total cost curve look like?",
                    "options": [
                        "an upward-sloping curve that increases at an increasing rate",
                        "an upward-sloping curve that increases at a decreasing rate",
                        "a downward-sloping curve",
                        "a horizontal straight line"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an upward-sloping curve that increases at an increasing rate",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-4. What is the marginal product of the second worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "15 students",
                        "20 students",
                        "22.5 students",
                        "25 students"
                    ],
                    "answer": "25 students",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-4. What is the marginal product of the third worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "15 students",
                        "20 students",
                        "35 students",
                        "60 students"
                    ],
                    "answer": "15 students",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-4. Charles’s math tutoring company experiences diminishing marginal productivity with the addition of the",
                    "options": [
                        "first worker.",
                        "second worker.",
                        "third worker.",
                        "fourth worker."
                    ],
                    "answer": "third worker.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-4. Suppose that Charles’s math tutoring company has a fixed cost of $50 per month for his cell phone. Each worker costs Charles $60 per day. As output increases from 0 to 45 students, Charles’s total cost curve",
                    "options": [
                        "increases but gets flatter.",
                        "increases and gets steeper.",
                        "decreases and gets flatter.",
                        "decreases but gets steeper."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases but gets flatter.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-4. Suppose that Charles’s math tutoring company has a fixed cost of $50 per month for his cell phone. Each worker costs Charles $60 per day. As output increases from 45 to 70 students, Charles’s total cost curve",
                    "options": [
                        "increases but gets flatter.",
                        "increases and gets steeper.",
                        "decreases and gets flatter.",
                        "decreases but gets steeper."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increases and gets steeper.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-5. The marginal product of the third worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "\"1,000 units.\"",
                        "900 units.",
                        "700 units.",
                        "500 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "700 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-5. The marginal product of the fourth worker is",
                    "options": [
                        "900 units.",
                        "800 units.",
                        "700 units.",
                        "500 units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "500 units.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-5. Diminishing marginal product begins with the addition of the",
                    "options": [
                        "second worker.",
                        "third worker.",
                        "fourth worker.",
                        "fifth worker."
                    ],
                    "answer": "third worker.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Production function | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-5. Assume that fixed costs are $500, and variable costs are $100 per worker. For this firm, what are the shapes of the production function and the total-cost curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "Both the production function and total-cost curve are increasing at an increasing rate.",
                        "Both the production function and total-cost curve are increasing at a decreasing rate.",
                        "\"The production function is increasing at a decreasing rate, whereas the total-cost function is increasing at an increasing rate.\"",
                        "\"The production function is increasing at an increasing rate, whereas the total-cost function is increasing at a decreasing rate.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"The production function is increasing at a decreasing rate, whereas the total-cost function is increasing at an increasing rate.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Each worker at the Wooden Chair Factory costs $12 per hour. The cost of each machine is $20 per day regardless of the number of chairs produced. If the factory produces at a rate of 70 chairs per hour and operates 8 hours per day, what is the factory’s total labor cost per day?",
                    "options": [
                        "$72",
                        "$112",
                        "$576",
                        "$616"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$576",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Each worker at the Wooden Chair Factory costs $12 per hour. The cost of each machine is $20 per day regardless of the number of chairs produced. What is the total daily cost of producing at a rate of 55 chairs per hour if the factory operates 8 hours per day?",
                    "options": [
                        "$480",
                        "$576",
                        "$520",
                        "$616"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$520",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Each worker at the Wooden Chair Factory costs $12 per hour. The cost of each machine is $20 per day regardless of the number of chairs produced. Assume the number of machines does not change. If the factory produces at a rate of 78 chairs per hour, what is the total machine cost per day?",
                    "options": [
                        "$20",
                        "$40",
                        "$240",
                        "We are unable to determine total machine costs from the information given."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$40",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Each worker at the Wooden Chair Factory costs $12 per hour. The cost of each machine is $20 per day regardless of the number of chairs produced. If the factory produces at a rate of 35 chairs per hour, what is the total labor cost per hour?",
                    "options": [
                        "$40",
                        "$48",
                        "$384",
                        "$424"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$48",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Assume the Wooden Chair Factory currently employs 5 workers. What is the marginal product of labor when the factory adds a 6th worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "5 chairs per hour",
                        "15 chairs per hour",
                        "25 chairs per hour",
                        "70 chairs per hour"
                    ],
                    "answer": "15 chairs per hour",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . Assume the Wooden Chair Factory currently employs 2 workers. What is the marginal product of labor when the factory adds a 3rd worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "5 chairs per hour",
                        "10 chairs per hour",
                        "20 chairs per hour",
                        "25 chairs per hour"
                    ],
                    "answer": "10 chairs per hour",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-6 . The Wooden Chair Factory experiences diminishing marginal product of labor with the addition of which worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "the third worker",
                        "the fourth worker",
                        "the fifth worker",
                        "the sixth worker"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the sixth worker",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3. The graph illustrates a typical",
                    "options": [
                        "total-cost curve.",
                        "production function.",
                        "production possibilities frontier.",
                        "fixed-cost curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total-cost curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve | Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3. The graph illustrates a typical total cost curve. Based on its shape, what does the corresponding production function look like?",
                    "options": [
                        "an upward-sloping curve that increases at an increasing rate",
                        "an upward-sloping curve that increases at a decreasing rate",
                        "a downward-sloping curve",
                        "a horizontal straight line"
                    ],
                    "answer": "an upward-sloping curve that increases at a decreasing rate",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve | Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3. Which of the following is true of the production function (not pictured) that underlies this total cost function?\n(i) Total output increases as the quantity of inputs increases but at a decreasing rate.\n(ii) Marginal product is diminishing for all levels of input usage.\n(iii) The slope of the production function decreases as the quantity of inputs increases.",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) only",
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "(i) and (iii) only",
                        "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve | Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3 . The changing slope of the total cost curve reflects",
                    "options": [
                        "decreasing average variable cost.",
                        "decreasing average total cost.",
                        "decreasing marginal product.",
                        "increasing fixed cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreasing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3 . Which of the following statements best captures the nature of the underlying production function (not pictured)?",
                    "options": [
                        "Output increases at a decreasing rate with additional units of input.",
                        "Output increases at an increasing rate with additional units of input.",
                        "Output decreases at a decreasing rate with additional units of input.",
                        "Output decreases at an increasing rate with additional units of input."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Output increases at a decreasing rate with additional units of input.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-3 . Assuming that the firm depicted produces cookies, which of the statements below is most consistent with the shape of the total cost curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "Producing an additional cookie is always more costly than producing the previous cookie.",
                        "Total production of cookies decreases with additional units of input.",
                        "\"Producing additional cookies is equally costly, regardless of how many cookies are already being produced.\"",
                        "Producing additional cookies becomes increasingly costly only when the number of cookies already being produced is large."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Producing an additional cookie is always more costly than producing the previous cookie.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-12\nIf Farmer Brown plants no seeds on his farm, he gets no harvest. If he plants 1 bag of seeds, he gets 5 bushels of wheat. If he plants 2 bags, he gets 9 bushels. If he plants 3 bags, he gets 12 bushels. A bag of seeds costs $120, and seeds are his only cost.\nRefer to Scenario 13-12. Farmer Brown’s production function exhibits",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing marginal product.",
                        "constant marginal product.",
                        "diminishing marginal product.",
                        "The production function is unrelated to the marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Production function | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-12\nIf Farmer Brown plants no seeds on his farm, he gets no harvest. If he plants 1 bag of seeds, he gets 5 bushels of wheat. If he plants 2 bags, he gets 9 bushels. If he plants 3 bags, he gets 12 bushels. A bag of seeds costs $120, and seeds are his only cost.\nRefer to Scenario 13-12. Farmer Brown’s total-cost curve is",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing at an increasing rate.",
                        "increasing at a decreasing rate.",
                        "increasing at a constant rate.",
                        "decreasing."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increasing at an increasing rate.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-13\nJoan grows pumpkins. If Joan plants no seeds on her farm, she gets no harvest. If she plants 1 bag of seeds, she gets 500 pumpkins. If she plants 2 bags, she gets 800 pumpkins. If she plants 3 bags, she gets 900 pumpkins. A bag of seeds costs $100, and seeds are her only cost.\nRefer to Scenario 13-13. Joan’s production function exhibits",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing marginal product.",
                        "decreasing marginal product.",
                        "constant marginal product.",
                        "Any of the above could be correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "decreasing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Production function | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-13\nJoan grows pumpkins. If Joan plants no seeds on her farm, she gets no harvest. If she plants 1 bag of seeds, she gets 500 pumpkins. If she plants 2 bags, she gets 800 pumpkins. If she plants 3 bags, she gets 900 pumpkins. A bag of seeds costs $100, and seeds are her only cost.\nRefer to Scenario 13-13. Joan’s total-cost curve is",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing at an increasing rate.",
                        "increasing at a decreasing rate.",
                        "increasing at a constant rate.",
                        "decreasing."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increasing at an increasing rate.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Production function | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements about a production function is correct for a firm that uses labor to produce output?",
                    "options": [
                        "The production function depicts the relationship between the quantity of labor and the quantity of output.",
                        "The slope of the production function measures marginal product.",
                        "\"The slopes of the production function and the total cost curve are inversely related; if one is increasing, the other is decreasing.\"",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A total-cost curve shows the relationship between the",
                    "options": [
                        "quantity of an input used and the total cost of production.",
                        "quantity of output produced and the total cost of production.",
                        "total cost of production and profit.",
                        "total cost of production and total revenue."
                    ],
                    "answer": "quantity of output produced and the total cost of production.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If the total cost curve gets steeper as output increases, the firm is experiencing",
                    "options": [
                        "diseconomies of scale.",
                        "economies of scale.",
                        "diminishing marginal product.",
                        "increasing marginal product."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "David’s firm experiences diminishing marginal product for all ranges of inputs. The total cost curve associated with David’s firm",
                    "options": [
                        "gets flatter as output increases.",
                        "gets steeper as output increases.",
                        "is constant for all ranges of output.",
                        "is unrelated to the production function."
                    ],
                    "answer": "gets steeper as output increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector3": {
            "title": "The Various Measures of Cost",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Some costs do not vary with the quantity of output produced. Those costs are called",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal costs.",
                        "average costs.",
                        "fixed costs.",
                        "explicit costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "fixed costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following costs do not vary with the amount of output a firm produces?",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed costs",
                        "fixed costs and average fixed costs",
                        "marginal costs and average fixed costs",
                        "fixed costs"
                    ],
                    "answer": "fixed costs",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Fixed costs can be defined as costs that",
                    "options": [
                        "vary inversely with production.",
                        "vary in proportion with production.",
                        "are incurred only when production is large enough.",
                        "are incurred even if nothing is produced."
                    ],
                    "answer": "are incurred even if nothing is produced.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In the short run, a firm incurs fixed costs",
                    "options": [
                        "only if it incurs variable costs.",
                        "only if it produces no output.",
                        "only if it produces a positive quantity of output.",
                        "whether it produces output or not."
                    ],
                    "answer": "whether it produces output or not.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a construction company that builds houses, which of the following costs would be a fixed cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"the $50,000 per year salary paid to a construction foreman\"",
                        "\"the $30,000 per year salary paid to the company's bookkeeper\"",
                        "\"the $10,000 per year premium paid to an insurance company\"",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a construction company that builds houses, which of the following costs would be a fixed cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "the $20 per hour wage paid to a construction foreman",
                        "\"the $30,000 per year salary paid to the company's bookkeeper\"",
                        "the $2 per worker-hour paid to the state government for workers’ compensation insurance",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"the $30,000 per year salary paid to the company's bookkeeper\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following costs of publishing a book is a fixed cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "author royalties of 5% per book",
                        "the costs of paper and binding",
                        "shipping and postage expenses",
                        "\"composition, typesetting, and jacket design for the book\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"composition, typesetting, and jacket design for the book\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular firm the only variable input into the production process is labor and that output equals zero when no workers are hired. In addition, suppose that when the firm hires 2 workers, the total cost of production is $100. When the firm hires 3 workers, the total cost of production is $120. In addition, assume that the variable cost per unit of labor is the same regardless of the number of units of labor that are hired. What is the firm's fixed cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "$40",
                        "$60",
                        "$80",
                        "$100"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$60",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Harry's Hotdogs is a small street vendor business owned by Harry Huggins. Harry is trying to get a better understanding of his costs by categorizing them as fixed or variable. Which of the following costs are most likely to be considered fixed costs?",
                    "options": [
                        "the cost of mustard",
                        "the cost of hotdog buns",
                        "wages paid to workers who sell hot dogs",
                        "the cost of bookkeeping services"
                    ],
                    "answer": "the cost of bookkeeping services",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose Jan started up a small lemonade stand business last month. Variable costs for Jan's lemonade stand now include the cost of",
                    "options": [
                        "building the lemonade stand.",
                        "hiring an artist to design a logo for her sign.",
                        "lemons and sugar.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "lemons and sugar.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose Jan started up a small lemonade stand business last month. Variable costs for Jan's lemonade stand now include the cost of",
                    "options": [
                        "lemons and sugar.",
                        "paper cups.",
                        "the wages paid to her hourly workers.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a firm produces nothing, which of the following costs will be zero?",
                    "options": [
                        "total cost",
                        "fixed cost",
                        "opportunity cost",
                        "variable cost"
                    ],
                    "answer": "variable cost",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a large firm that produces and sells automobiles, which of the following costs would be a variable cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "the $20 million payment that the firm pays each year for accounting services",
                        "the cost of the steel that is used in producing automobiles",
                        "the rent that the firm pays for office space in a suburb of St. Louis",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the cost of the steel that is used in producing automobiles",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "For a large firm that produces and sells automobiles, which of the following costs would be a variable cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "the unemployment insurance premium that the firm pays to the state of Missouri that is calculated based on the number of worker-hours that the firm uses",
                        "the cost of the steel that is used in producing automobiles",
                        "the cost of the electricity of running the machines on the factory floor",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a firm is able to put idle equipment to use by hiring another worker,",
                    "options": [
                        "variable costs will rise.",
                        "variable costs will fall.",
                        "fixed costs will fall.",
                        "both fixed costs and variable costs will rise."
                    ],
                    "answer": "variable costs will rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is the best example of a variable cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "monthly wage payments for hired labor",
                        "annual property tax payments for a building",
                        "monthly rent payments for a warehouse",
                        "annual insurance payments for a warehouse"
                    ],
                    "answer": "monthly wage payments for hired labor",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Total cost can be divided into two types of costs:",
                    "options": [
                        "fixed costs and variable costs.",
                        "fixed costs and marginal costs.",
                        "variable costs and marginal costs.",
                        "average costs and marginal costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "fixed costs and variable costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that a firm has only one variable input, labor, and firm output is zero when labor is zero. When the firm hires 6 workers it produces 90 units of output. Fixed cost of production are $6 and the variable cost per unit of labor is $10. The marginal product of the seventh unit of labor is 4. Given this information, what is the total cost of production when the firm hires 7 workers?",
                    "options": [
                        "$66",
                        "$76",
                        "$906",
                        "$946"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$76",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular firm the only variable input into the production process is labor and that output equals zero when no workers are hired. In addition, suppose that marginal cost of the third worker hired is $40, and the average total cost when three workers are hired is $50. What is the total cost of production when three workers are hired?",
                    "options": [
                        "$50",
                        "$90",
                        "$120",
                        "$150"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$150",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Cindy’s Car Wash has average variable costs of $2 and average fixed costs of $3 when it produces 100 units of output (car washes). The firm's total cost is",
                    "options": [
                        "$100.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$300.",
                        "$500."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$500.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The cost of producing the typical unit of output is the firm's",
                    "options": [
                        "average total cost.",
                        "opportunity cost.",
                        "variable cost.",
                        "marginal cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost is equal to",
                    "options": [
                        "output/total cost.",
                        "total cost - total quantity of output.",
                        "average variable cost + total fixed cost.",
                        "total cost/output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "total cost/output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost equals",
                    "options": [
                        "change in total costs divided by quantity produced.",
                        "change in total costs divided by change in quantity produced.",
                        "(fixed costs + variable costs) divided by quantity produced.",
                        "(fixed costs + variable costs) divided by change in quantity produced."
                    ],
                    "answer": "(fixed costs + variable costs) divided by quantity produced.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost tells us the",
                    "options": [
                        "\"total cost of the first unit of output, if total cost is divided evenly over all the units produced.\"",
                        "\"cost of a typical unit of output, if total cost is divided evenly over all the units produced.\"",
                        "\"cost of the last unit of output, if total cost does not include a fixed cost component.\"",
                        "variable cost of a firm that is producing at least one unit of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"cost of a typical unit of output, if total cost is divided evenly over all the units produced.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following expressions is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost = (change in quantity of output)/(change in total cost)",
                        "average total cost = (total cost)/(quantity of output)",
                        "total cost = variable cost + marginal cost",
                        "average variable cost = (quantity of output)/(total variable cost)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost = (total cost)/(quantity of output)",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost (ATC) is calculated as follows:",
                    "options": [
                        "ATC = (change in total cost)/(change in quantity of output).",
                        "ATC = (change in total cost)/(change in quantity of input).",
                        "ATC = (total cost)/(quantity of output).",
                        "ATC = (total cost)/(quantity of input)."
                    ],
                    "answer": "ATC = (total cost)/(quantity of output).",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following measures of cost is best described as \"the cost of a typical unit of output if total cost is divided evenly over all the units produced?\"",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed cost",
                        "average variable cost",
                        "average total cost",
                        "marginal cost"
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Larry's Lunchcart is a small street vendor business. If Larry makes 15 pretzels in his first hour of business and incurs a total cost of $16.50, his average total cost per pretzel is",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.10.",
                        "$6.50.",
                        "$15.00.",
                        "$16.50."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$1.10.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At Bert's Bootery, the total cost of producing twenty pairs of boots is $400. The marginal cost of producing the twenty-first pair of boots is $83. We can conclude that the",
                    "options": [
                        "average variable cost of 21 pairs of boots is $23.",
                        "average total cost of 21 pairs of boots is $23.",
                        "average total cost of 21 pairs of boots is $15.09.",
                        "marginal cost of the 20th pair of boots is $20."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost of 21 pairs of boots is $23.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular firm the only variable input into the production process is labor and that output equals zero when no workers are hired. In addition, suppose that when the firm hires 4 workers, the firm produces 50 units of output. If the fixed cost of production is $4, the variable cost per unit of labor is $20, and the marginal product of labor for the fifth unit of labor is 2, what is the average total cost of production when the firm hires 5 workers?",
                    "options": [
                        "$2.00",
                        "$20.00",
                        "$20.80",
                        "$22.80"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$2.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Tom’s Tent Company has total fixed costs of $300,000 per year. The firm's average variable cost is $80 for 10,000 tents. At that level of output, the firm's average total costs equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$80",
                        "$90",
                        "$100",
                        "$110"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$110",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The Wacky Widget company has total fixed costs of $100,000 per year. The firm's average variable cost is $5 for 10,000 widgets. At that level of output, the firm's average total costs equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$10",
                        "$15",
                        "$100",
                        "$150"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular firm the only variable input into the production process is labor and that output equals zero when no workers are hired. In addition, suppose that the average total cost when 5 units of output are produced is $30, and the marginal cost of the sixth unit of output is $60. What is the average total cost when six units are produced?",
                    "options": [
                        "$10",
                        "$25",
                        "$30",
                        "$35"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$35",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that a firm has only one variable input, labor, and firm output is zero when labor is zero. When the firm hires 6 workers the firm produces 90 units of output. Fixed costs of production are $6 and the variable cost per unit of labor is $10. The marginal product of the seventh unit of labor is 4. Given this information, what is the average total cost of production when the firm hires 7 workers?",
                    "options": [
                        "$10.06",
                        "$9.64",
                        "81 cents",
                        "70 cents"
                    ],
                    "answer": "81 cents",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The Wacky Widget company has total fixed costs of $100,000 per year. The firm’s average variable cost is $10 for 10,000 widgets. At that level of output, the firm’s average total costs equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$10",
                        "$15",
                        "$20",
                        "$25"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$20",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Brady Industries has average variable costs of $1 and average total costs of $3 when it produces 500 units of output. The firm's total fixed costs equal",
                    "options": [
                        "$2.",
                        "$4.",
                        "\"$1,000.\"",
                        "\"$2,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$1,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "Fixed costs are constant.",
                        "Variable costs change as output changes.",
                        "Average fixed costs are constant.",
                        "Average total costs are typically U-shaped."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Average fixed costs are constant.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose that for a particular firm the only variable input into the production process is labor and that output equals zero when no workers are hired. In addition, suppose that when four units of output are produced, the total cost is $175, and the average variable cost is $33.75. What would the average fixed cost be if ten units were produced?",
                    "options": [
                        "$4",
                        "$10",
                        "$40",
                        "$135"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$4",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A firm produces 400 units of output at a total cost of $1,200. If total variable costs are $1,000,",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed cost is 50 cents.",
                        "average variable cost is $2.",
                        "average total cost is $2.50.",
                        "average total cost is 50 cents."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average fixed cost is 50 cents.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A firm produces 300 units of output at a total cost of $1,000. If fixed costs are $100,",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed cost is $10.",
                        "average variable cost is $3.",
                        "average total cost is $4.",
                        "average total cost is $5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average variable cost is $3.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Variable cost divided by quantity produced is",
                    "options": [
                        "average total cost.",
                        "marginal cost.",
                        "profit.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Variable cost divided by the change in quantity produced is",
                    "options": [
                        "average variable cost.",
                        "marginal cost.",
                        "average total cost.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "None of the above is correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Cindy’s Car Wash has average variable costs of $2 and average total costs of $3 when it produces 100 units of output (car washes). The firm's total variable cost is",
                    "options": [
                        "$100.",
                        "$200.",
                        "$300.",
                        "$500."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$200.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Consider the following information about baseball production at Bobby's Baseball Factory:\n\nWorker,Marginal Product\n1,3\n2,5\n3,8\n4,10\n5,7\n6,4\n7,2\n\nBobby pays all his workers the same wage, and labor is his only variable cost. From this information we can conclude that Bobby's average variable cost decreases",
                    "options": [
                        "\"as output rises from 0 to 10, but rises after that.\"",
                        "\"as output rises from 0 to 26, but rises after that.\"",
                        "\"as output rises from 0 to 33, but increases after that.\"",
                        "continually as output rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"as output rises from 0 to 26, but rises after that.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A firm produces 400 units of output at a total cost of $1,200. If fixed costs are $200,",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed cost is $2.",
                        "average variable cost is $2.50.",
                        "average total cost is $4.",
                        "average total cost is $5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average variable cost is $2.50.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of A?\n\nTable 13-7\nThe Flying Elvis Copter Rides\nQuantity,Total,Cost,Fixed,Cost,Variable,Cost,Marginal,Cost,Average,Fixed,Cost,Average,Variable,Cost,Average,Total,Cost\n0,$50,$50,$0,--,--,--,--\n1,$150,A,B,C,D,E,F\n2,G,H,I,$120,J,K,L\n3,M,N,O,P,Q,$120,R",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of B?\n\nTable 13-7\nThe Flying Elvis Copter Rides\nQuantity,Total,Cost,Fixed,Cost,Variable,Cost,Marginal,Cost,Average,Fixed,Cost,Average,Variable,Cost,Average,Total,Cost\n0,$50,$50,$0,--,--,--,--\n1,$150,A,B,C,D,E,F\n2,G,H,I,$120,J,K,L\n3,M,N,O,P,Q,$120,R",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$100",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of C?\n\nTable 13-7\nThe Flying Elvis Copter Rides\nQuantity,Total,Cost,Fixed,Cost,Variable,Cost,Marginal,Cost,Average,Fixed,Cost,Average,Variable,Cost,Average,Total,Cost\n0,$50,$50,$0,--,--,--,--\n1,$150,A,B,C,D,E,F\n2,G,H,I,$120,J,K,L\n3,M,N,O,P,Q,$120,R",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$100",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of D?\n\nTable 13-7\nThe Flying Elvis Copter Rides\nQuantity,Total,Cost,Fixed,Cost,Variable,Cost,Marginal,Cost,Average,Fixed,Cost,Average,Variable,Cost,Average,Total,Cost\n0,$50,$50,$0,--,--,--,--\n1,$150,A,B,C,D,E,F\n2,G,H,I,$120,J,K,L\n3,M,N,O,P,Q,$120,R",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of E?\n\nTable 13-7\nThe Flying Elvis Copter Rides\nQuantity,Total,Cost,Fixed,Cost,Variable,Cost,Marginal,Cost,Average,Fixed,Cost,Average,Variable,Cost,Average,Total,Cost\n0,$50,$50,$0,--,--,--,--\n1,$150,A,B,C,D,E,F\n2,G,H,I,$120,J,K,L\n3,M,N,O,P,Q,$120,R",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$150"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$100",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of F?",
                    "options": [
                        "$50",
                        "$100",
                        "$150",
                        "$200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$150",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of G?",
                    "options": [
                        "$30",
                        "$120",
                        "$220",
                        "$270"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$270",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of H?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0",
                        "$50",
                        "$220",
                        "$270"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of I?",
                    "options": [
                        "$110",
                        "$120",
                        "$220",
                        "$270"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$220",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of J?",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$110",
                        "$220"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of K?",
                    "options": [
                        "$25",
                        "$50",
                        "$110",
                        "$220"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$110",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of L?",
                    "options": [
                        "$60",
                        "$135",
                        "$240",
                        "$270"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$135",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of M?",
                    "options": [
                        "$50",
                        "$140",
                        "$360",
                        "$410"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$410",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of N?",
                    "options": [
                        "$50",
                        "$140",
                        "$360",
                        "$410"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of O?",
                    "options": [
                        "$40",
                        "$140",
                        "$360",
                        "$410"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$360",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of P?",
                    "options": [
                        "$50",
                        "$140",
                        "$360",
                        "$410"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$140",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of Q?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16.67",
                        "$50",
                        "$136.67",
                        "$360"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$16.67",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-7. What is the value of R?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16.67",
                        "$50",
                        "$136.67",
                        "$360"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$136.67",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-8. What is the average fixed cost of producing 5 units of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "$4",
                        "$5",
                        "$40",
                        "$44"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$4",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-8. What is the average variable cost of producing 5 units of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "$4",
                        "$5",
                        "$40",
                        "$44"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$40",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-8. What is the marginal cost of producing the fifth unit of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "$4",
                        "$40",
                        "$50",
                        "$70"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$70",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-8. What is the shape of the marginal cost curve for this firm?",
                    "options": [
                        "constant",
                        "upward-sloping",
                        "downward-sloping",
                        "U-shaped"
                    ],
                    "answer": "upward-sloping",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . The average fixed cost of producing 5 posters is",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.00.",
                        "$2.00.",
                        "$3.00.",
                        "$5.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$2.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . The average variable cost of producing 4 posters is",
                    "options": [
                        "$2.00.",
                        "$2.50.",
                        "$3.33.",
                        "$5.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$2.50.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . The total cost of producing 1 poster is",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.00.",
                        "$10.00.",
                        "$11.00.",
                        "$22.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$11.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . The marginal cost of producing the 6th poster is",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.00.",
                        "$3.50.",
                        "$5.00.",
                        "$6.00."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$6.00.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . What is the variable cost of producing 0 posters?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0.00",
                        "$1.00",
                        "$10.00",
                        "$10.00"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$0.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . What is the marginal cost of producing the 1st poster?",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.00",
                        "$10.00",
                        "$11.00",
                        "It can't be determined from the information given."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-9 . What is the variable cost of producing 5 posters?",
                    "options": [
                        "$13.00",
                        "$14.00",
                        "$15.00",
                        "It can't be determined from the information given."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-10\nEileen’s Elegant Earrings produces pairs of earrings for its mail order catalogue business. Each pair is shipped in a separate box. She rents a small room for $150 a week in the downtown business district that serves as her factory. She can hire workers for $275 a week. There are no implicit costs.\nRefer to Table 13-10 . What is the marginal product of the second worker?",
                    "options": [
                        "110",
                        "200",
                        "260",
                        "300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "300",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-10\nEileen’s Elegant Earrings produces pairs of earrings for its mail order catalogue business. Each pair is shipped in a separate box. She rents a small room for $150 a week in the downtown business district that serves as her factory. She can hire workers for $275 a week. There are no implicit costs.\nRefer to Table 13-10 . What is the total cost associated with making 890 boxes of earrings per week?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$1,250\"",
                        "\"$1,325\"",
                        "\"$1,400\"",
                        "\"$1,575\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$1,250\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-10\nEileen’s Elegant Earrings produces pairs of earrings for its mail order catalogue business. Each pair is shipped in a separate box. She rents a small room for $150 a week in the downtown business district that serves as her factory. She can hire workers for $275 a week. There are no implicit costs.\nRefer to Table 13-10 . During the week of July 4th, Eileen doesn't produce any earrings. What are her costs during the week?",
                    "options": [
                        "$0",
                        "$150",
                        "$275",
                        "$425"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$150",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-10\nEileen’s Elegant Earrings produces pairs of earrings for its mail order catalogue business. Each pair is shipped in a separate box. She rents a small room for $150 a week in the downtown business district that serves as her factory. She can hire workers for $275 a week. There are no implicit costs.\nRefer to Table 13-10 . One week, Eileen earns a profit of $125. If her revenue for the week is $1100, how many boxes of earrings did she produce?",
                    "options": [
                        "140",
                        "330",
                        "780",
                        "950"
                    ],
                    "answer": "780",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-10\nEileen’s Elegant Earrings produces pairs of earrings for its mail order catalogue business. Each pair is shipped in a separate box. She rents a small room for $150 a week in the downtown business district that serves as her factory. She can hire workers for $275 a week. There are no implicit costs.\nRefer to Table 13-10 . Eileen has received an order for 3,000 boxes of earrings for next week. If she expects that the trend in the marginal product of labor will continue in the same direction, it is most likely that her best decision will be to",
                    "options": [
                        "not commit to meeting the order until she can move to a larger room and hire more workers to produce the earrings.",
                        "close her business until she is able to hire more productive workers.",
                        "hire about 12 new workers and hope she can satisfy the order.",
                        "commit to meeting the order and then take three weeks to complete the job."
                    ],
                    "answer": "not commit to meeting the order until she can move to a larger room and hire more workers to produce the earrings.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-11\nTeacher's Helper is a small company that has a subcontract to produce instructional materials for disabled children in public school districts. The owner rents several small rooms in an office building in the suburbs for $600 a month and has leased computer equipment that costs $480 a month.\nRefer to Table 13-11 . What is the marginal cost of creating the tenth instructional module in a given month?",
                    "options": [
                        "$900",
                        "\"$1,250\"",
                        "\"$2,500\"",
                        "\"$3,060\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$2,500\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-11\nTeacher's Helper is a small company that has a subcontract to produce instructional materials for disabled children in public school districts. The owner rents several small rooms in an office building in the suburbs for $600 a month and has leased computer equipment that costs $480 a month.\nRefer to Table 13-11 . What is the average variable cost for the month if 6 instructional modules are produced?",
                    "options": [
                        "$180.00",
                        "$533.33",
                        "$700.00",
                        "$713.33"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$533.33",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-11\nTeacher's Helper is a small company that has a subcontract to produce instructional materials for disabled children in public school districts. The owner rents several small rooms in an office building in the suburbs for $600 a month and has leased computer equipment that costs $480 a month.\nRefer to Table 13-11 . What is the average fixed cost for the month if 9 instructional modules are produced?",
                    "options": [
                        "$108.00",
                        "$120.00",
                        "$150.00",
                        "$811.11"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$120.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-11\nTeacher's Helper is a small company that has a subcontract to produce instructional materials for disabled children in public school districts. The owner rents several small rooms in an office building in the suburbs for $600 a month and has leased computer equipment that costs $480 a month.\nRefer to Table 13-11 . How many instructional modules are produced when marginal cost is $1,300?",
                    "options": [
                        "4",
                        "5",
                        "7",
                        "8"
                    ],
                    "answer": "8",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-11\nTeacher's Helper is a small company that has a subcontract to produce instructional materials for disabled children in public school districts. The owner rents several small rooms in an office building in the suburbs for $600 a month and has leased computer equipment that costs $480 a month.\nRefer to Table 13-11 . One month, Teacher's Helper produced 18 instructional modules. What was the average fixed cost for that month?",
                    "options": [
                        "$60",
                        "$108",
                        "$811",
                        "It can't be determined from the information given."
                    ],
                    "answer": "$60",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the fixed cost of production at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$12",
                        "$20",
                        "$25",
                        "$51"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$25",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the variable cost of producing 5 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$64",
                        "$85",
                        "$90",
                        "$100"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$85",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the variable cost of producing 8 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$120",
                        "$140",
                        "$155",
                        "$160"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$160",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the total cost of producing 2 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$48",
                        "$53",
                        "$58",
                        "$62"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$53",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the total cost of producing 7 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$140",
                        "$150",
                        "$153",
                        "$158"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$158",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average variable cost of producing 3 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$14",
                        "$15",
                        "$16",
                        "$17"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average variable cost of producing 6 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16",
                        "$17",
                        "$18",
                        "$19"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$18",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average fixed cost of producing 3 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.67",
                        "$2.67",
                        "$5.33",
                        "$8.33"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$8.33",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average fixed cost of producing 8 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$2.12",
                        "$3.13",
                        "$20.00",
                        "$24.37"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$3.13",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average total cost of producing 2 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$14.00",
                        "$18.50",
                        "$22.50",
                        "$26.50"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$26.50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the average total cost of producing 6 cakes at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$16.34",
                        "$22.00",
                        "$22.17",
                        "$22.57"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$22.17",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the marginal cost of the 2nd cake at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$14",
                        "$15",
                        "$28",
                        "$34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$15",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the marginal cost of the 4th cake at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$13",
                        "$15",
                        "$19",
                        "$64"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$19",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-12\nBetty’s Bakery\nRefer to Table 13-12. What is the marginal cost of the 8th cake at Betty’s Bakery?",
                    "options": [
                        "$20",
                        "$27",
                        "$160",
                        "$185"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$27",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-13 . What is the total fixed cost for this firm?",
                    "options": [
                        "$20",
                        "$30",
                        "$40",
                        "$50"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$40",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-13 . What is average fixed cost when output is 40 units?",
                    "options": [
                        "$1.00",
                        "$3.32",
                        "$5.00",
                        "$8.00"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$1.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "Marginal-cost curve",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-14: If Farmer Brown plants no seeds on his farm, he gets no harvest. If he plants 1 bag of seeds, he gets 5 bushels of wheat. If he plants 2 bags, he gets 9 bushels. If he plants 3 bags, he gets 12 bushels. A bag of seeds costs $120, and seeds are his only cost. Refer to Scenario 13-14. Farmer Brown’s marginal-cost curve is",
                    "options": [
                        "increasing.",
                        "decreasing.",
                        "constant.",
                        "U-shaped."
                    ],
                    "answer": "increasing.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Scenario 13-16: A certain firm produces and sells staplers. Last year, it produced 7,000 staplers and sold each stapler for $6. In producing the 7,000 staplers, it incurred variable costs of $28,000 and a total cost of $45,000. Refer to Scenario 13-16. The firm's fixed cost was",
                    "options": [
                        "\"$7,000.\"",
                        "\"$17,000.\"",
                        "\"$28,000.\"",
                        "\"$42,000.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"$17,000.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 116,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The amount by which total cost rises when the firm produces one additional unit of output is called",
                    "options": [
                        "average cost.",
                        "marginal cost.",
                        "fixed cost.",
                        "variable cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 122,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A firm has a fixed cost of $500 in its first year of operation. When the firm produces 100 units of output, its total costs are $3,500. When it produces 101 units of output, its total costs are $3,750. What is the marginal cost of producing the 101st unit of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "$250",
                        "$275",
                        "$340.91",
                        "$350"
                    ],
                    "answer": "$250",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 131,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost | Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If Franco's Pizza Parlor knows that the marginal cost of the 500th pizza is $3.50 and that the average total cost of making 499 pizzas is $3.30, then",
                    "options": [
                        "average total costs are rising at Q = 500.",
                        "average total costs are falling at Q = 500.",
                        "total costs are falling at Q = 500.",
                        "average variable costs must be falling."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total costs are rising at Q = 500.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 139,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost | Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The fundamental reason that marginal cost eventually rises as output increases is because of",
                    "options": [
                        "economies of scale.",
                        "diseconomies of scale.",
                        "diminishing marginal product.",
                        "rising average fixed cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 147,
                    "topic": "Cost curves | Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5. Curve A represents which type of cost curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost",
                        "average total cost",
                        "average variable cost",
                        "average fixed cost"
                    ],
                    "answer": "average fixed cost",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 151,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5. Curve D represents which type of cost curve?",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost",
                        "average total cost",
                        "average variable cost",
                        "average fixed cost"
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal cost",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 152,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5. Which curve is most likely to represent marginal cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "D",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 153,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5 . Curve D is increasing because",
                    "options": [
                        "of diminishing marginal product.",
                        "of increasing marginal product.",
                        "\"marginal product first increases, then decreases.\"",
                        "\"marginal product first decreases, then increases.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "of diminishing marginal product.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 154,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5 . Curve A is always declining because",
                    "options": [
                        "of diminishing marginal product.",
                        "we are dividing fixed costs by higher and higher levels of output.",
                        "\"marginal product first increases, then decreases.\"",
                        "\"marginal product first decreases, then increases.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "we are dividing fixed costs by higher and higher levels of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 155,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-5 . Curve D intersects curve C",
                    "options": [
                        "where the firm maximizes profit.",
                        "at the minimum of average fixed cost.",
                        "at the efficient scale.",
                        "where fixed costs equal variable costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "at the efficient scale.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 156,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-6 . Which of the following can be inferred from the figure above?\n(i) Marginal cost is increasing at all levels of output.\n(ii) Marginal product is increasing at low levels of output.\n(iii) Marginal product is decreasing at high levels of output.",
                    "options": [
                        "(i) and (ii) only",
                        "(ii) and (iii) only",
                        "(i) and (iii) only",
                        "(ii) only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "(ii) and (iii) only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 157,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Fixed costs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-6 . Why doesn’t the total cost curve begin at the origin (the point 0,0)?",
                    "options": [
                        "because variable costs are positive when output is zero",
                        "because fixed costs are positive when output is zero",
                        "because the firm is producing at the efficient scale",
                        "because the firm is maximizing profits"
                    ],
                    "answer": "because fixed costs are positive when output is zero",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 158,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-7 . Which of the figures represents the total cost curve for a typical firm?",
                    "options": [
                        "Figure 1",
                        "Figure 2",
                        "Figure 3",
                        "Figure 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Figure 2",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 159,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-7 . Which of the figures represents the marginal cost curve for a typical firm?",
                    "options": [
                        "Figure 1",
                        "Figure 2",
                        "Figure 3",
                        "Figure 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Figure 1",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 160,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-7 . Which of the figures represents the production function for a typical firm?",
                    "options": [
                        "Figure 1",
                        "Figure 2",
                        "Figure 3",
                        "Figure 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Figure 4",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 161,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-8. The efficient scale of production occurs at which quantity?",
                    "options": [
                        "A",
                        "B",
                        "C",
                        "D"
                    ],
                    "answer": "C",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 162,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-8. Quantity C represents the output level where the firm",
                    "options": [
                        "maximizes profits.",
                        "minimizes total costs.",
                        "produces at the efficient scale.",
                        "minimizes marginal costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "produces at the efficient scale.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 163,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-8. Quantity B represents the output level where the firm",
                    "options": [
                        "maximizes profits.",
                        "minimizes average variable costs.",
                        "produces at the efficient scale.",
                        "minimizes marginal costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "minimizes average variable costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 164,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following factors is most likely to shift IBM's total cost and marginal cost curves downward?",
                    "options": [
                        "a technological advance resulting in increased productivity",
                        "higher property taxes charged by the municipal government",
                        "increased wages to attract additional computer operators",
                        "a reduction in subsidies from the state government"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a technological advance resulting in increased productivity",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 165,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If marginal cost is equal to average total cost, then",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost is minimized.",
                        "average total cost is minimized.",
                        "average variable cost is minimized.",
                        "marginal cost is zero."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is minimized.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 166,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"If marginal cost is rising, then average total cost is rising.\"",
                        "\"If marginal cost is rising, then average variable cost is rising.\"",
                        "\"If average variable cost is rising, then marginal cost is minimized.\"",
                        "\"If average total cost is rising, then marginal cost is greater than average total cost.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"If average total cost is rising, then marginal cost is greater than average total cost.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 167,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The average fixed cost curve",
                    "options": [
                        "always declines with increased levels of output.",
                        "always rises with increased levels of output.",
                        "declines as long as it is above marginal cost.",
                        "declines as long as it is below marginal cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "always declines with increased levels of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 168,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost is very high when a small amount of output is produced because",
                    "options": [
                        "average variable cost is high.",
                        "average fixed cost is high.",
                        "marginal cost is high.",
                        "marginal product is high."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average fixed cost is high.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 169,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When marginal cost is less than average total cost,",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost must be falling.",
                        "average variable cost must be falling.",
                        "average total cost is falling.",
                        "average total cost is rising."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is falling.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 170,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When marginal cost exceeds average total cost,",
                    "options": [
                        "average fixed cost must be rising.",
                        "average total cost must be rising.",
                        "average total cost must be falling.",
                        "marginal cost must be falling."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost must be rising.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 171,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Average total cost is increasing whenever",
                    "options": [
                        "total cost is increasing.",
                        "marginal cost is increasing.",
                        "marginal cost is less than average total cost.",
                        "marginal cost is greater than average total cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal cost is greater than average total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 172,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Marginal cost is equal to average total cost when",
                    "options": [
                        "average variable cost is falling.",
                        "average fixed cost is rising.",
                        "marginal cost is at its minimum.",
                        "average total cost is at its minimum."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is at its minimum.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 173,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If marginal cost is below average total cost, then average total cost",
                    "options": [
                        "is constant.",
                        "is falling.",
                        "is rising.",
                        "may rise or fall depending on the size of fixed costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "is falling.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 174,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At all levels of production higher than the point where the marginal cost curve crosses the average variable cost curve, average variable cost",
                    "options": [
                        "rises.",
                        "remains unaffected.",
                        "falls.",
                        "All of the above are possible depending on the shape of the marginal cost curve."
                    ],
                    "answer": "rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 175,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements about costs is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"When marginal cost is less than average total cost, average total cost is rising.\"",
                        "The total cost curve is U-shaped.",
                        "\"As the quantity of output increases, marginal cost eventually rises.\"",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"As the quantity of output increases, marginal cost eventually rises.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 176,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whenever marginal cost is greater than average total cost,",
                    "options": [
                        "average total cost is rising.",
                        "marginal cost is falling.",
                        "average total cost is falling.",
                        "Both b and c are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is rising.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 177,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At what level of output will average variable cost equal average total cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "when marginal cost equals average total cost",
                        "for all levels of output in which average variable cost is falling",
                        "when marginal cost equals average variable cost",
                        "\"There is no level of output where this occurs, as long as fixed costs are positive.\""
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"There is no level of output where this occurs, as long as fixed costs are positive.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 178,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average fixed cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following must always be true as the quantity of output increases?",
                    "options": [
                        "Marginal cost must rise.",
                        "Average total cost must rise.",
                        "Average variable cost must rise.",
                        "Average fixed cost must fall."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Average fixed cost must fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 179,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Average variable cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "The marginal cost of the fifth unit of output equals the total cost of five units minus the total cost of four units.",
                        "The total variable cost of seven units equals the average variable cost of seven units times seven.",
                        "\"If marginal cost is rising, then average variable cost must be rising.\"",
                        "The marginal cost of the fifth unit of output equals the total variable cost of five units minus the total variable cost of four units."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"If marginal cost is rising, then average variable cost must be rising.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 180,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When marginal cost is rising, average variable cost",
                    "options": [
                        "must be rising.",
                        "must be falling.",
                        "must be constant.",
                        "could be rising or falling."
                    ],
                    "answer": "could be rising or falling.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 181,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When marginal cost is greater than average cost, average cost is",
                    "options": [
                        "rising.",
                        "falling.",
                        "constant.",
                        "The direction of change in average cost cannot be determined from this information."
                    ],
                    "answer": "rising.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 182,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When average cost is greater than marginal cost, marginal cost must be",
                    "options": [
                        "rising.",
                        "falling.",
                        "constant.",
                        "The direction of change in marginal cost cannot be determined from this information."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The direction of change in marginal cost cannot be determined from this information.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 183,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following is not a property of a firm's cost curves?",
                    "options": [
                        "Marginal cost must eventually rise as a result of diminishing marginal product.",
                        "Average total cost is U-shaped.",
                        "Economies of scale will exist when average total cost falls as output rises.",
                        "Average total cost will cross marginal cost at the minimum of marginal cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Average total cost will cross marginal cost at the minimum of marginal cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 184,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If marginal cost is greater than average total cost, then",
                    "options": [
                        "profits are increasing.",
                        "economies of scale are becoming greater.",
                        "average total cost remains constant.",
                        "average total cost is increasing."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is increasing.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 185,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The minimum points of the average variable cost and average total cost curves occur where the",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal cost curve lies below the average variable cost and average total cost curves.",
                        "marginal cost curve intersects those curves.",
                        "average variable cost and average total cost curves intersect.",
                        "slope of total cost is the smallest."
                    ],
                    "answer": "marginal cost curve intersects those curves.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 186,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                    "options": [
                        "\"For most producers, the average total cost curve never crosses the marginal cost curve.\"",
                        "The average fixed cost curve must eventually rise.",
                        "\"The average total cost curve first rises, then falls with increased output.\"",
                        "The marginal cost curve eventually rises with the quantity of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The marginal cost curve eventually rises with the quantity of output.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 187,
                    "topic": "Cost curves  | Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The marginal cost curve crosses the average total cost curve at",
                    "options": [
                        "the efficient scale.",
                        "the minimum point on the average total cost curve.",
                        "a point where the marginal cost curve is rising.",
                        "All of the above are correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 188,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The efficient scale of the firm is the quantity of output that",
                    "options": [
                        "maximizes marginal product.",
                        "maximizes profit.",
                        "minimizes average total cost.",
                        "minimizes average variable cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "minimizes average total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 189,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The firm's efficient scale is the quantity of output that minimizes",
                    "options": [
                        "average total cost.",
                        "average fixed cost.",
                        "average variable cost.",
                        "marginal cost."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 190,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "When a firm is operating at an efficient scale,",
                    "options": [
                        "average variable cost is minimized.",
                        "average fixed cost is minimized.",
                        "average total cost is minimized.",
                        "marginal cost is minimized."
                    ],
                    "answer": "average total cost is minimized.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector4": {
            "title": "Costs in the Short Run and in the Long Run",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Short run",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "One assumption that distinguishes short-run cost analysis from long-run cost analysis for a profit-maximizing firm is that in the short run,",
                    "options": [
                        "output is not variable.",
                        "the number of workers used to produce the firm's product is fixed.",
                        "the size of the factory is fixed.",
                        "there are no fixed costs."
                    ],
                    "answer": "the size of the factory is fixed.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Short run | Long run",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The total cost to the firm of producing zero units of output is",
                    "options": [
                        "zero in both the short run and the long run.",
                        "its fixed cost in the short run and zero in the long run.",
                        "its fixed cost in both the short run and the long run.",
                        "its variable cost in both the short run and the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "its fixed cost in the short run and zero in the long run.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "The long-run average total cost curve is always",
                    "options": [
                        "\"flatter than the short-run average total cost curve, but not necessarily horizontal.\"",
                        "horizontal.",
                        "falling as output increases.",
                        "rising as output increases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "\"flatter than the short-run average total cost curve, but not necessarily horizontal.\"",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Economies of scale occur when a firm’s",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal costs are constant as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are decreasing as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are increasing as output increases.",
                        "marginal costs are equal to average total costs for all levels of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "long-run average total costs are decreasing as output increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In the long run Firm A incurs total costs of $1,050 when output is 30 units and $1,200 when output is 40 units. Firm A exhibits",
                    "options": [
                        "diseconomies of scale because total cost is rising as output rises.",
                        "diseconomies of scale because average total cost is rising as output rises.",
                        "economies of scale because total cost is rising as output rises.",
                        "economies of scale because average total cost is falling as output rises."
                    ],
                    "answer": "economies of scale because average total cost is falling as output rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Constant returns to scale occur when a firm’s",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal costs are constant as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are decreasing as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are increasing as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs do not vary as output increases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "long-run average total costs do not vary as output increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Diseconomies of scale occur when a firm’s",
                    "options": [
                        "marginal costs are constant as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are decreasing as output increases.",
                        "long-run average total costs are increasing as output increases.",
                        "marginal costs are equal to average total costs for all levels of output."
                    ],
                    "answer": "long-run average total costs are increasing as output increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-9. The figure below depicts average total cost functions for a firm that produces automobiles. Which curve represents the long-run average total cost?",
                    "options": [
                        "ATCA",
                        "ATCB",
                        "ATCC",
                        "ATCD"
                    ],
                    "answer": "ATCD",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-9. The figure below depicts average total cost functions for a firm that produces automobiles. The firm experiences economies of scale at which output levels?",
                    "options": [
                        "output levels less than M",
                        "output levels between M and N",
                        "output levels greater than N",
                        "All of the above are correct as long as the firm is operating in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "output levels less than M",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-9 . This firm experiences diseconomies of scale at what output levels?",
                    "options": [
                        "output levels greater than N",
                        "output levels between M and N",
                        "output levels less than M",
                        "All of the above are correct as long as the firm is operating in the long run."
                    ],
                    "answer": "output levels greater than N",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-9 . At output levels greater than N, the firm experiences",
                    "options": [
                        "economies of scale.",
                        "constant returns to scale.",
                        "diseconomies of scale.",
                        "minimum efficient scale."
                    ],
                    "answer": "diseconomies of scale.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-10 . The three average total cost curves on the diagram labeled ATC1, ATC2, and ATC3 most likely correspond to three different",
                    "options": [
                        "time horizons.",
                        "products.",
                        "firms.",
                        "factory sizes."
                    ],
                    "answer": "factory sizes.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-10 . The firm experiences economies of scale if it changes its level of output from",
                    "options": [
                        "Q 1 to Q 2.",
                        "Q 2 to Q 3.",
                        "Q 3 to Q4.",
                        "Q 4 to Q 5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Q 1 to Q 2.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-10 . The firm experiences constant returns to scale if it changes its level of output from",
                    "options": [
                        "Q 1 to Q 2.",
                        "Q 2 to Q 4.",
                        "Q 1 to Q 3.",
                        "Q 4 to Q 5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Q 2 to Q 4.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Refer to Figure 13-10 . The firm experiences diseconomies of scale if it changes its level of output from",
                    "options": [
                        "Q 1 to Q 2.",
                        "Q 2 to Q 3.",
                        "Q 3 to Q 4.",
                        "Q 4 to Q 5."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Q 4 to Q 5.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-14\nListed in the table are the long-run total costs for three different firms.\nRefer to Table 13-14. Which firm is experiencing diseconomies of scale?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm A only",
                        "Firm B only",
                        "Firm C only",
                        "Firm A and Firm B only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm C only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-14\nListed in the table are the long-run total costs for three different firms.\nRefer to Table 13-14. Which firm is experiencing constant returns to scale?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm A only",
                        "Firm B only",
                        "Firm C only",
                        "Firm A and Firm B only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm B only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Which firm has constant returns to scale over the entire range of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm 1",
                        "Firm 2",
                        "Firm 3",
                        "Firm 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm 4",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Which firm has diseconomies of scale over the entire range of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm 1 only",
                        "Firms 1 and 2 only",
                        "Firm 3 only",
                        "Firm 4 only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm 3 only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Which firm has economies of scale over the entire range of output?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm 1 only",
                        "Firms 1 and 2 only",
                        "Firm 2 only",
                        "Firm 3 only"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm 2 only",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Which firm has economies of scale and then diseconomies of scale as output increases from 1 to 7?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm 1",
                        "Firm 2",
                        "Firm 3",
                        "Firm 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm 1",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Which firm's long-run marginal cost decreases as output increases?",
                    "options": [
                        "Firm 1",
                        "Firm 2",
                        "Firm 3",
                        "Firm 4"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Firm 2",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Table 13-15\nConsider the following table of long-run total cost for four different firms:\nRefer to Table 13-15. Firm 1's efficient scale occurs at what quantity?",
                    "options": [
                        "2",
                        "3",
                        "4",
                        "5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "3",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector5": {
            "title": "True / False & Conclusion",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In his book, An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith described a visit he made to a",
                    "options": [
                        "car factory.",
                        "pin factory.",
                        "washing machine factory.",
                        "farm."
                    ],
                    "answer": "pin factory.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In his book, An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith credits economies of scale to",
                    "options": [
                        "competition.",
                        "opportunity costs.",
                        "specialization.",
                        "incentives."
                    ],
                    "answer": "specialization.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "In setting the production level, a firm's cost curves",
                    "options": [
                        "by themselves do not tell us what decisions the firm will make.",
                        "dictate what decisions the firm will make.",
                        "have no bearing on what decisions the firm will make.",
                        "None of the above is correct."
                    ],
                    "answer": "by themselves do not tell us what decisions the firm will make.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The economic field of industrial organization examines how firms’ decisions about prices and quantities depend on the market conditions they face.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Industrial organization",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The field of industrial organization addresses how the number of firms affects prices in a market and the efficiency of the market outcome.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "A firm’s total profit equals its marginal revenue minus its marginal cost.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Profit equals total revenue minus total cost.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Economic profit | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The difference between economic profit and accounting profit is that economic profit is calculated based on both implicit and explicit costs whereas accounting profit is calculated based on explicit costs only.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit  | Economic profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Accounting profit is greater than or equal to economic profit.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit  | Economic profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Economic profit is greater than or equal to accounting profit.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Although economists and accountants treat many costs differently, they both treat the cost of capital the same.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "Accounting profit",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Accountants keep track of the money that flows into and out of firms.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "When economists speak of a firm's costs, they are usually excluding the opportunity costs.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Economists and accountants both include forgone income as a cost to a small business owner.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Anna borrows $5,000 from a bank and withdraws $1,000 from her personal savings to start a coffee shop. The interest rate is 5 percent for both the bank loan and her personal savings. Her opportunity cost of capital is $250.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Economists and accountants usually disagree on the inclusion of implicit costs into the cost analysis of a firm.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Implicit costs are costs that do not require an outlay of money by the firm.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Accountants often ignore implicit costs.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Implicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The opportunity cost of capital is an implicit cost almost every business incurs.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "An example of an explicit cost would be the wages that a business owner pays her employees.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Explicit costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "An example of an explicit cost for the owner of a tattoo parlor would be the wages that she could earn if she worked as a graphic artist for an advertising agency.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Diminishing marginal productivity implies decreasing total product.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Diminishing marginal product exists when the total cost curve becomes horizontal as outputs increases.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Diminishing marginal product exists when the production function becomes flatter as inputs increase.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "A second or third worker may have a higher marginal product than the first worker in certain circumstances.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The typical total-cost curve is U-shaped.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Average-fixed-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The average-fixed-cost curve is constant.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Total cost  | Fixed costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "In the short run, if a firm produces nothing, total costs are zero.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If a firm produces nothing, it still incurs its fixed costs.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Fixed costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "For a typical firm, fixed costs increase in direct proportion to the increases in output.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve  | Production function",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The shape of the total-cost curve is unrelated to the shape of the production function.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Total-cost curve  | Production function",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The shape of the total-cost curve is inversely related to the shape of the production function.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The graph of the production function plots total cost versus quantity of output.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "Marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Suppose that a worker can produce 100 units of output in 7 hours. In the 8th hour, he can produce 12 units of output. The worker can produce 112 units of output in 8 hours.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Marginal costs are costs that do not vary with the quantity of output produced.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "Cost curves",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Several related measures of cost can be derived from a firm's total cost.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Variable costs usually change as the firm alters the quantity of output produced.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "Variable costs",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Variable costs equal fixed costs when nothing is produced.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The cost of producing an additional unit of a good is not the same as the average cost of the good.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "Average variable cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Average variable cost is equal to total variable cost divided by quantity of output.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The average-total-cost curve is unaffected by diminishing marginal product.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Average-total-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The average-total-cost curve reflects the shape of both the average-fixed-cost and average-variable-cost curves.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If the marginal-cost curve is rising, then so is the average-total-cost curve.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Average total cost  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The marginal-cost curve intersects the average-total-cost curve at the minimum point of the average-total-cost curve.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Average total cost  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The marginal-cost curve intersects the average-total-cost curve at the minimum point of the marginal-cost curve.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "Average total cost  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The marginal-cost curve intersects the average-total-cost curve at the output level where average fixed costs are zero.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "Average total cost | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Assume Jack received all As in his classes last semester. If Jack gets all Bs in his classes this semester, his GPA may or may not fall.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Average total cost and marginal cost express information that is already contained in a firm's total cost.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Average total cost reveals how much total cost will change as the firm alters its level of production.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If the marginal cost of producing the tenth unit of output is $3, and if the average total cost of producing the tenth unit of output is $2, then at ten units of output, average total cost is rising.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If the marginal cost of producing the tenth unit of output is $2.50, and if the average total cost of producing the tenth unit of output is $3, then at ten units of output, average total cost is rising.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost  | Average total cost",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If the marginal cost of producing the fifth unit of output is higher than the marginal cost of producing the fourth unit of output, then at five units of output, average total cost must be rising.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "Marginal cost  | Marginal product",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The shape of the marginal cost curve tells a producer something about the marginal product of her workers.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "Marginal-cost curve | Average-fixed-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The marginal-cost curve intersects the average-fixed-cost curve at the minimum of marginal cost.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "Marginal-cost curve | Average-total-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "When average total cost is above marginal cost, average total cost is rising.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "Efficient scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "When average total cost rises if a producer either increases or decreases production, then the firm is said to be operating at efficient scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "Long run",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "In the long run, a factory is usually considered a fixed input.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Long run",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Fixed costs are those costs that remain fixed no matter how long the time horizon is.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Long run",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The fact that many inputs are fixed in the short run but variable in the long run has little impact on the firm's cost curves.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Long run",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "There is general agreement among economists that the long-run time period exceeds one year.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Long run | Average-total-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "As a firm moves along its long-run average cost curve, it is adjusting the size of its factory to the quantity of production.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Long run | Average-total-cost curve",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Because of the greater flexibility that firms have in the long run, all short-run cost curves lie on or above the long-run curve.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Economies of scale often arise because higher production levels allow specialization among workers.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "If long-run average total cost is rising, then the firm is experiencing economies of scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "In some cases, specialization allows larger factories to produce goods at a lower average cost than smaller factories.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "The use of specialization to achieve economies of scale is one reason modern societies are as prosperous as they are.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "When a firm experiences economies of scale, long-run average total cost falls as the quantity of output increases.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Diseconomies of scale often arise because higher production levels allow specialization among workers.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm A is experiencing economies of scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm A is experiencing constant returns to scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "Constant returns to scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm B is experiencing constant returns to scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm B is experiencing diseconomies of scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "Diseconomies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm C is experiencing diseconomies of scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Refer to Table 13-16. Firm C is experiencing economies of scale.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Adam Smith's example of the pin factory demonstrates that economies of scale result from specialization.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Economies of scale",
                    "type": "true_false",
                    "question": "Adam Smith describes a visit to a car factory when discussing economies of scale in his book An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations.",
                    "options": [
                        "True",
                        "False"
                    ],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        "sector6": {
            "title": "Short Answer",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Opportunity cost",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "What are opportunity costs? How do explicit and implicit costs relate to opportunity costs?",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "The opportunity cost of an item refers to all those things that must be forgone to acquire that item. Both explicit and implicit costs are included as opportunity costs.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "Economic profit  | Accounting profit",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "A key difference between accountants and economists is their different treatment of the cost of capital. Does this cause an accountant's estimate of total costs to be higher or lower than an economist's estimate? Explain.",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "An accountant would not include the forgone interest income that the money could have earned elsewhere if it had not been invested in the business. Therefore, an accountant's estimate of total cost will be less than an economist's.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "Production function",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "The production function depicts a relationship between which two variables? Also, draw a production function that exhibits diminishing marginal product.",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "The production function depicts the relationship between output and a given input. The graph below shows output increasing but at a decreasing rate as the quantity of inputs increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product  | Total-cost curve",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "How would a production function that exhibits decreasing marginal product affect the shape of the total cost curve? Explain or draw a graph.",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "The total cost curve will increase at an increasing rate, or in other words, the total cost curve gets steeper as the amount produced rises.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Diminishing marginal product  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "What effect, if any, does diminishing marginal product have on the shape of the marginal cost curve?",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "Diminishing marginal product causes the marginal cost curve to rise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Average total cost",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "Bob Edwards owns a bagel shop. Bob hires an economist who assesses the shape of the bagel shop's average total cost (ATC) curve as a function of the number of bagels produced. The results indicate a U-shaped average total cost curve. Bob's economist explains that ATC is U-shaped for two reasons. The first is the existence of diminishing marginal product, which causes it to rise. What would be the second reason? Assume that the marginal cost curve is linear. (Hint: The second reason relates to average fixed cost)",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "Average fixed cost always declines as output rises because fixed cost is being spread over a larger number of units, thus causing the average total cost curve to fall.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Average total cost  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "If the average total cost curve is falling, what is necessarily true of the marginal cost curve? If the average total cost curve is rising, what is necessarily true of the marginal cost curve?",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "When average total cost curve is falling, marginal cost is below ATC. If the average total cost curve is rising, marginal cost is above ATC.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "Average total cost  | Marginal cost",
                    "type": "short_answer",
                    "question": "According to the mathematical laws that govern the relationship between average total cost and marginal cost, where must these two curves intersect?",
                    "options": [],
                    "answer": "The two curves will cross at the minimum point on the average total cost curve.",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        }
    }
}
